<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knative – Knative contribution guidelines</title>
    <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Knative contribution guidelines on Knative</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://knative.dev/community/contributing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Contributor covenant code of conduct</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;our-pledge&#34;&gt;Our Pledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as
contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in our project and
our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body
size, disability, ethnicity, gender identity and expression, level of
experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance,
race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-standards&#34;&gt;Our Standards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment
include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using welcoming and inclusive language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being respectful of differing viewpoints and experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gracefully accepting constructive criticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing on what is best for the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showing empathy towards other community members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of unacceptable behavior by participants include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of sexualized language or imagery and unwelcome sexual attention or
advances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trolling, insulting/derogatory comments, and personal or political attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public or private harassment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing others&#39; private information, such as a physical or electronic
address, without explicit permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other conduct which could reasonably be considered inappropriate in a
professional setting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Our Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the Technical Oversight Committee are responsible for clarifying the
standards of acceptable behavior and are expected to take appropriate and fair
corrective action in response to any instances of unacceptable behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TOC members have the right and responsibility to remove, edit, or reject
comments, commits, code, wiki edits, issues, and other contributions that are
not aligned to this Code of Conduct, or to ban temporarily or permanently any
contributor for other behaviors that they deem inappropriate, threatening,
offensive, or harmful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct applies both within project spaces and in public spaces
when an individual is representing the project or its community. Examples of
representing a project or community include using an official project e-mail
address, posting via an official social media account, or acting as an appointed
representative at an online or offline event. Representation of a project may be
further defined and clarified by project maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enforcement&#34;&gt;Enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instances of abusive, harassing, or otherwise unacceptable behavior may be
reported by contacting the Technical Oversight Committee at
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:knative-code-of-conduct@googlegroups.com&#34;&gt;knative-code-of-conduct@googlegroups.com&lt;/a&gt;. All complaints will be reviewed and
investigated and will result in a response that is deemed necessary and
appropriate to the circumstances. The project team is obligated to maintain
confidentiality with regard to the reporter of an incident. Further details of
specific enforcement policies may be posted separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TOC members who do not follow or enforce the Code of Conduct in good faith may
face temporary or permanent repercussions as determined by other members of the
project&amp;rsquo;s leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct is adapted from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/a&gt;,
version 1.4, available at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct.html&#34;&gt;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative contributor guidelines</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/contributing/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;So, you want to hack on Knative? Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following sections outline the process all changes to the Knative
repositories go through. All changes, regardless of whether they are from
newcomers to the community or from the core team follow the same process and are
given the same level of review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#working-groups&#34;&gt;Working groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#team-values&#34;&gt;Team values&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#contributor-license-agreements&#34;&gt;Contributor license agreements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#design-documents&#34;&gt;Design documents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#contributing-documentation&#34;&gt;Contributing documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#contributing-a-feature&#34;&gt;Contributing a feature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#setting-up-to-contribute-to-knative&#34;&gt;Setting up to contribute to Knative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#pull-requests&#34;&gt;Pull requests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-groups&#34;&gt;Working groups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knative contributors community is organized into a set of
&lt;a href=&#34;./working-groups/WORKING-GROUPS.md&#34;&gt;working groups&lt;/a&gt;. Any contribution to
Knative should be started by first engaging with the appropriate working group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All members of the Knative community must abide by the
&lt;a href=&#34;./CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. Only by respecting each other can we
develop a productive, collaborative community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team-values&#34;&gt;Team values&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We promote and encourage a set of &lt;a href=&#34;./VALUES.md&#34;&gt;shared values&lt;/a&gt; to improve our
productivity and inter-personal interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributor-license-agreements&#34;&gt;Contributor license agreements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d love to accept your patches! But before we can take them, you will have to
fill out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.developers.google.com&#34;&gt;Google CLA&lt;/a&gt;. (Make sure to fill
out the CLA with the same email address you used to register for Github.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are CLA&amp;rsquo;ed, we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to accept your pull requests. This is
necessary because you own the copyright to your changes, even after your
contribution becomes part of this project. So this agreement simply gives us
permission to use and redistribute your contributions as part of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Your contributions are verified using the email address for which you use
to sign the CLA. Therefore,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/articles/setting-your-commit-email-address&#34;&gt;setting your GitHub account to private&lt;/a&gt;
is unsupported because all commits from private accounts are sent from the
&lt;code&gt;noreply&lt;/code&gt; email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-documents&#34;&gt;Design documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any substantial design deserves a design document
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1FvezfvBghevCRoZUmN3SoTVtm6f_u_r5f94MEa4jNIA/edit&#34;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt;).
Design documents are written with Google Docs and should be shared with the
community by adding the doc to our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0AM-QGZJ-HUA8Uk9PVA&#34;&gt;Team Drive&lt;/a&gt;
and sending an email to the appropriate working group&amp;rsquo;s mailing list to let
people know the doc is there. To get write access to the drive, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to
be a &lt;a href=&#34;./ROLES.md#member&#34;&gt;member&lt;/a&gt; of the Knative organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team drive is shared with the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-users&#34;&gt;knative-users@&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt; Google
groups for reading and editing, respectively. Access to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-users&#34;&gt;knative-users@&lt;/a&gt; is
unlimited, while
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt; requires
human review. If you&amp;rsquo;re not part of one of those groups, the first time you try
to access the team drive or a specific doc, you&amp;rsquo;ll be asked to request
permission. Please join one of the above groups (you can join knative-users and
later join knative-dev if you want immediate access).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributing-documentation&#34;&gt;Contributing documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about contributing to the Knative documentation, see
&lt;a href=&#34;./docs/DOCS-CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;DOCS-CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt;. A lot of the information on
this page still applies, but you&amp;rsquo;ll find the specifics about the docs process
there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contributing-a-feature&#34;&gt;Contributing a feature&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process for adding features to Knative can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;./mechanics/FEATURE-TRACKS.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-to-contribute-to-knative&#34;&gt;Setting up to contribute to Knative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving/blob/main/README.md&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; to learn
about the Knative source base and setting up your
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving/blob/main/DEVELOPMENT.md&#34;&gt;development environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pull-requests&#34;&gt;Pull requests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gubernator.knative.dev&#34;&gt;gubernator&lt;/a&gt; instance that provides a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gubernator.knative.dev/pr&#34;&gt;pull request dashboard&lt;/a&gt; so you can see which
PRs you need to take action on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re working on an existing issue, simply respond to the issue and express
interest in working on it. This helps other people know that the issue is
active, and hopefully prevents duplicated efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To submit a proposed change:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fork the affected repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new branch for your changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop the code/fix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new test cases. In the case of a bug fix, the tests should fail without
your code changes. For new features try to cover as many variants as
reasonably possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify the documentation as necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify all CI status checks pass, and work to make them pass if failing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general rule is that all PRs should be 100% complete - meaning they should
include all test cases and documentation changes related to the change. A
significant exception is work-in-progress PRs. These should be indicated by a
&lt;code&gt;[WIP]&lt;/code&gt; prefix in the PR title. WIP PRs should not be merged as long as they are
marked WIP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When ready, if you have not already done so, sign a
&lt;a href=&#34;#contributor-license-agreements&#34;&gt;contributor license agreement&lt;/a&gt; and submit the
PR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project uses
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/test-infra/tree/master/prow&#34;&gt;Prow&lt;/a&gt; to assign
reviewers to the PR, set labels, run tests automatically, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;./REVIEWING.md&#34;&gt;Reviewing and Merging Pull Requests&lt;/a&gt; for the PR review and
merge process used for Knative and for more information about
&lt;a href=&#34;./REVIEWING.md#prow&#34;&gt;Prow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub issues can be used to report bugs or submit feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reporting a bug please include the following key pieces of information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The version of the project you were using (version number, git commit, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating system you are using&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exact, minimal, steps needed to reproduce the issue. Submitting a 5 line
script will get a much faster response from the team than one that&amp;rsquo;s hundreds
of lines long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;third-party-code&#34;&gt;Third-party code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All third-party code must be placed in &lt;code&gt;vendor/&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;third_party/&lt;/code&gt; folders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;vendor/&lt;/code&gt; folder is managed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/golang/dep&#34;&gt;dep&lt;/a&gt; and stores
the source code of third-party Go dependencies. &lt;code&gt;vendor/&lt;/code&gt; folder should not be
modified manually.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other third-party code belongs in &lt;code&gt;third_party/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third-party code must include licenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-exclusive list of code that must be places in &lt;code&gt;vendor/&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;third_party/&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open source, free software, or commercially-licensed code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools or libraries or protocols that are open source, free software, or
commercially licensed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Derivative works of third-party code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excerpts from third-party code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-a-new-third-party-dependency-to-third_party-folder&#34;&gt;Adding a new third-party dependency to &lt;code&gt;third_party/&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a sub-folder under &lt;code&gt;third_party/&lt;/code&gt; for each component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In each sub-folder, make sure there is a file called LICENSE which contains
the appropriate license text for the dependency. If one doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist then
create it. More details on this below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check in a pristine copy of the code with LICENSE and METADATA files. You do
not have to include unused files, and you can move or rename files if
necessary, but do not modify the contents of any files yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the pristine copy is merged into master, you may modify the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The license for the code must be in a file named LICENSE. If it was distributed
like that, you&amp;rsquo;re good. If not, you need to make LICENSE be a file containing
the full text of the license. If there&amp;rsquo;s another file in the distribution with
the license in it, rename it to LICENSE (e.g., rename a LICENSE.txt or COPYING
file to LICENSE). If the license is only available in the comments or at a URL,
extract and copy the text of the license into LICENSE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may optionally document the generation of the LICENSE file in the
local_modifications field of the METADATA file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are multiple licenses for the code, put the text of all the licenses
into LICENSE along with separators and comments as to the applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative Governance Framework</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/governance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Knative Governance is broken into three components. At a high level, the Knative
Steering Committee (KSC) is the &amp;ldquo;root&amp;rdquo; level governance body, but the Knative
Trademark Committee (KTC) operates within a protected governance umbrella in
parallel with the KSC. As such, the KSC may investigate and enforce Code of
Conduct actions against members of the KTC, but may not alter the charter or
governance of the KTC rules. The Tech Oversight Committee (TOC) operates
entirely within the governance definitions delineated by the KSC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-and-operations&#34;&gt;Community and Operations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;./STEERING-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;Knative Steering Committee&lt;/a&gt; is responsible for the
general health of the Knative community. Responsibilities include maintaining
the governance framework, code of conduct, community meetings, communication
platforms, and test resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;trademarks&#34;&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;./TRADEMARK-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;Knative Trademark Committee&lt;/a&gt; is responsible for
management, licensing, and conformance verification of Knative logos, names, and
trademarks, including the definition of what &amp;ldquo;Knative&amp;rdquo; is and the definition and
rules for usage of derived marks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology-and-software-implementation&#34;&gt;Technology and Software Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;./TECH-OVERSIGHT-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;Knative Technical Oversight Committee&lt;/a&gt; is
responsible for the technical oversight, release process, and integration of the
technology components of the Knative project. Most day-to-day work is delegated
by the TOC to various subject-specific working groups.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative processes and guidelines</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/mechanics/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This directory provides a location for documenting and recording common Knative
community practices. At the moment, these practices (except for the formation of
Working Groups) are recommendations which individual working groups may choose
to adopt, rather than requirements. Each working group should document their
processes; either in their own repo or in a pointer to these docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./WORKING-GROUP-PROCESSES.md&#34;&gt;Working group formation and management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./FEATURE-TRACKS.md&#34;&gt;Feature Tracks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./RELEASE-VERSIONING-PRINCIPLES.md&#34;&gt;Releases and API versioning principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- TODO(argent/eallred): Add recommended process for:

- Issue triage and milestone management
- Feature management
- Experimental features
- Alpha/beta/GA maturity

--&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative working group</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/working-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/working-groups/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Most community activity is organized into &lt;em&gt;working groups&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working groups follow the &lt;a href=&#34;../CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing&lt;/a&gt; guidelines although
each of these groups may operate a little differently depending on their needs
and workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the need arises, a new working group can be created. See the
&lt;a href=&#34;../mechanics/WORKING-GROUP-PROCESSES.md&#34;&gt;working group processes&lt;/a&gt; for working
group proposal and creation procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The working groups generate design docs which are kept in a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0AM-QGZJ-HUA8Uk9PVA&#34;&gt;shared drive&lt;/a&gt;
and are available for anyone to read and comment on. The shared drive currently
grants read access to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-users&#34;&gt;knative-users@&lt;/a&gt; and edit
and comment access to the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt; Google
group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some working groups (mostly those with a plug-in or extension model) end up
responsible for a set of GitHub repos, one for each extension. This allows for
easier dependency management; in these cases, one or more repo prefix names will
be recorded as canonical &amp;ldquo;extension names&amp;rdquo; to allow WGs to be responsible for
their own namespace without needing to get TOC approval for each repo name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, all working groups should hold regular meetings, which should be
added to the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;shared knative calendar&lt;/a&gt;
WG leads should have access to be able to create and update events on this
calendar, and should invite &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:knative-dev@googlegroups.com&#34;&gt;knative-dev@googlegroups.com&lt;/a&gt; to working group
meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;calendar-import&#34;&gt;Calendar import&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using Google Calendar, the above should work. If you&amp;rsquo;re using some
other system (Apple Calendar or Outlook, for example),
&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/ical/knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com/public/basic.ics&#34;&gt;here is an iCal export of the community calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.office.com/en-us/article/import-or-subscribe-to-a-calendar-in-outlook-on-the-web-503ffaf6-7b86-44fe-8dd6-8099d95f38df&#34;&gt;Follow these directions to import into Outlook Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.office.com/en-us/article/See-your-Google-Calendar-in-Outlook-C1DAB514-0AD4-4811-824A-7D02C5E77126&#34;&gt;Follow these directions for desktop Outlook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/guide/calendar/import-or-export-calendars-icl1023/mac&#34;&gt;Follow the import directions to import into Apple Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;working-groups&#34;&gt;Working Groups&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current working groups are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#api-core&#34;&gt;API Core&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#client&#34;&gt;Client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#documentation&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#eventing&#34;&gt;Eventing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#event-delivery&#34;&gt;Event Delivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#eventing-sources&#34;&gt;Eventing Sources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#networking&#34;&gt;Networking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#operations&#34;&gt;Operations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#productivity&#34;&gt;Productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#scaling&#34;&gt;Scaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#user-experience&#34;&gt;User Experience&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!-- TODO add charters for each group --&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-core&#34;&gt;API Core&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;API
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving/tree/main/pkg/apis/serving&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/pkg/tree/main/webhook&#34;&gt;validation&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/pkg/tree/main/controller&#34;&gt;semantics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TODO (historical, was created before formal WG process)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HqLJ8uNm5KmKPlMzQmbfDy0haybEUrPydsp7gNBrl20/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wednesdays 10:30a-11:00a PST &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HqLJ8uNm5KmKPlMzQmbfDy0haybEUrPydsp7gNBrl20/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1eCSmaqJ4LYcuS3TlOqjW0xETnzLmo6Q9&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;knative/serving&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/serving-api&#34;&gt;#serving-api&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG Leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/api-core-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/api-core-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/dprotaso.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dave Protasowski&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dprotaso&#34;&gt;dprotaso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;client&#34;&gt;Client&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/client&#34;&gt;Client&lt;/a&gt;, CLI, client libraries, and client
conventions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./client/CHARTER.md&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cD7NkJJhSBpo2Q6RBHrbrSe6R5zjTZgO_YDGAluQ_oI/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tuesdays, alternating between 10:30a-11:00a Pacific and 3:30p-4:00p Central European every two weeks&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar Invitation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cD7NkJJhSBpo2Q6RBHrbrSe6R5zjTZgO_YDGAluQ_oI/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1QffYD_XM0vqaXDvFlZVsJHAT6-AahJCO&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/client&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;knative/client&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;code&gt;kn-plugin-*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev&#34;&gt;#cli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/client-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/client-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/navidshaikh.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Navid Shaikh&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/navidshaikh&#34;&gt;navidshaikh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/rhuss.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Roland Huß&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rhuss&#34;&gt;rhuss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;documentation&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knative documentation, especially the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/docs/&#34;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;
repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./docs/CHARTER.md&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-docs&#34;&gt;knative-docs@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/13-neXVH-1n1ELWgukSzySnWj-4X6UB2pGGws2z2NH3M/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Every Tuesday, 9:30-10:30am PST&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/13-neXVH-1n1ELWgukSzySnWj-4X6UB2pGGws2z2NH3M/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1cMXOSiGo1kiWl0WXeGz8nV6esLetJS2f&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/docs&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;knative/docs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/website&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;knative/website&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/docs&#34;&gt;#docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/docs-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/docs-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eventing&#34;&gt;Eventing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event sources, bindings, FaaS framework, and orchestration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter / Mission&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/main/docs/mission.md&#34;&gt;Enable asynchronous application development through event delivery from anywhere.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Xha-FeunojN49OJN7W0WBnPMcRtp1ycYpbkiir6XsE0/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wednesdays 9:00a-9:30a PST&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Xha-FeunojN49OJN7W0WBnPMcRtp1ycYpbkiir6XsE0/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/16A4v6Qv9MNSumpy6geGm0u1izDqAfiNo&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;knative/eventing&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;code&gt;eventing-*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/eventing&#34;&gt;#eventing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/eventing-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/eventing-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/vaikas.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ville Aikas (Technical)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vaikas&#34;&gt;vaikas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/lionelvillard.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lionel Villard (Technical)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IBM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lionelvillard&#34;&gt;lionelvillard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/devguyio.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ahmed Abdalla (Execution)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/devguyio&#34;&gt;devguyio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;event-delivery&#34;&gt;Event Delivery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event delivery data plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./delivery/CHARTER.md&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/10pvpEAb6DZ0mplmSeg8fEAmmJtqimt03GEHRieOcMig/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tuesdays 8:30a-9:00a PST&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/10pvpEAb6DZ0mplmSeg8fEAmmJtqimt03GEHRieOcMig/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1YcyeckwBNPApxh8vHAlscYe_w7sIA5TA&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;knative/eventing&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing-contrib&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;knative/eventing-contrib&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, (shares &lt;code&gt;eventing-*&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/eventing-delivery&#34;&gt;#eventing-delivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/channel-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/channel-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/matzew.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Matthias Wessendorf&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matzew&#34;&gt;matzew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/slinkydeveloper.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Francesco Guardiani&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slinkydeveloper&#34;&gt;slinkydeveloper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eventing-sources&#34;&gt;Eventing Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event producers and frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./sources/CHARTER.md&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19txVRqA6_eY6ClGqoLRa0gPB50Ok7PT6_B6zDP1KtKQ/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tuesdays 8:30a-9:00a PST&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/19txVRqA6_eY6ClGqoLRa0gPB50Ok7PT6_B6zDP1KtKQ/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/13idi0QRqj1vsp5X0vDGfUOULhIyeeLaG&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repo prefixes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(shares &lt;code&gt;eventing-*&lt;/code&gt; with the eventing WG)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/eventing-sources&#34;&gt;#eventing-sources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/source-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/source-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/n3wscott.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scott Nichols&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/n3wscott&#34;&gt;n3wscott&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/lionelvillard.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lionel Villard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IBM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lionelvillard&#34;&gt;lionelvillard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;networking&#34;&gt;Networking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inbound and outbound network connectivity for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving&#34;&gt;serving&lt;/a&gt; workloads. Specific areas of
interest include: load balancing, routing, DNS configuration and TLS support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TODO (historical, was created before formal WG process)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/18m2XUDe-5QMFFBpLhIC7ozFnq12niYAqebtS3nMorhk/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thursdays at 9:00a-9:30a PST&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/18m2XUDe-5QMFFBpLhIC7ozFnq12niYAqebtS3nMorhk/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1bx86aDXjXhylDvFmEpjWSMn8o80_2_nR&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repos&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;net-*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/networking&#34;&gt;#networking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/networking-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/networking-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/nak3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kenjiro Nakayama&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nak3&#34;&gt;nak3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/tcnghia.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nghia Tran&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Microsoft&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tcnghia&#34;&gt;tcnghia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/ZhiminXiang.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Zhimin Xiang&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ZhiminXiang&#34;&gt;ZhiminXiang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operations&#34;&gt;Operations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing, assessing system health and maintaining Knative clusters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./operations/CHARTER.md&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1m9oFlelI292Fzwi_sRUTrf69I-CcCwEVXkGcMAjDYqM/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tuesdays at 10:00am PST &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1m9oFlelI292Fzwi_sRUTrf69I-CcCwEVXkGcMAjDYqM/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1GgBCtyWWGx8v8PHGbzJ_tu7DROyBl6x7&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repo prefixes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/operations&#34;&gt;#operations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/operations-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/operations-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/houshengbo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vincent Hou&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IBM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/houshengbo&#34;&gt;houshengbo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;productivity&#34;&gt;Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project health, test framework, continuous integration &amp;amp; deployment, release,
performance/scale/load testing infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./productivity/CHARTER.md&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/16go22yTCiaNBtdjghhrqSxnsWkMbxRs4i_gSIezGzUk/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thursdays, 10am PST&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/16go22yTCiaNBtdjghhrqSxnsWkMbxRs4i_gSIezGzUk/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1_1oWL7skjVt2211T0aagpwzDEfWmEIQK&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repo prefixes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;actions-*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/productivity&#34;&gt;#productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/productivity-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/productivity-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/chizhg.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chi Zhang&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chizhg&#34;&gt;chizhg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/n3wscott.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scott Nichols&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/n3wscott&#34;&gt;n3wscott&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scaling&#34;&gt;Scaling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoscaling behavior of Knative Serving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TODO (historical, was created before formal WG process)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-hezRkkLhnCkkEm6S09SkQR-BpF5xpTyhethYL5Zm6w/edit#&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wednesdays at 9:30am PST &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-hezRkkLhnCkkEm6S09SkQR-BpF5xpTyhethYL5Zm6w/edit#&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1IDDkJ3FD47xFSHY3iA9U2Q8th3Cwdo0K&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repo prefixes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/autoscaling&#34;&gt;#autoscaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/autoscaling-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/autoscaling-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/markusthoemmes.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Markus Thömmes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markusthoemmes&#34;&gt;markusthoemmes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/vagababov.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Victor Agababov&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vagababov&#34;&gt;vagababov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security concerns across Knative components&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter / Mission&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/194bECSbxPIONzhgGj1g9tccUsP8I-M7WIvbBqcT-tXY/edit&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1b-aCADlUBo2FZEDp5z5XoXlfUT6CvED339fcAdKY66o/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tuesdays at 9am PST &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1b-aCADlUBo2FZEDp5z5XoXlfUT6CvED339fcAdKY66o/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1yOy_yU5vvUTFuxeYvhlY7uzIL4c4SSzX&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Repo prefixes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/security&#34;&gt;#security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/security-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/security-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/evankanderson.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evan Anderson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/evankanderson&#34;&gt;evankanderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/julz.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Julian Friedman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IBM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/julz&#34;&gt;julz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;user-experience&#34;&gt;User Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User Experience concerns across Knative components&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charter / Mission&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1K_LGymgqedAzRS0ACdVtJH1ktQxrf1OatfxzIb6LjU0/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forum&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1NSlGHen5Dh6c2A0LGavGWibddWrlSLV_PbEbMpNjSTU/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tuesday at 9:30am PST &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1NSlGHen5Dh6c2A0LGavGWibddWrlSLV_PbEbMpNjSTU/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Roadmap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/projects/20&#34;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1XzZGqV7yHo38d_l7rH1uSIrbQp3JlbBP?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev/messages/user-experience&#34;&gt;#user-experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Repository&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/ux&#34;&gt;#user-experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Github Team WG leads&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/knative/teams/ux-wg-leads/members&#34;&gt;@knative/ux-wg-leads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leads&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/omerbensaadon.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Omer Bensaadon&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/omerbensaadon&#34;&gt;omerbensaadon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/csantanapr.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Carlos Santana&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IBM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/csantanapr&#34;&gt;csantanapr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative Repository Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/repository-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/repository-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This document outlines a structure for creating and associating code
repositories with the Knative project. It also describes how and when
repositories are removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-repositories&#34;&gt;Core Repositories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core repositories are considered core components of Knative. They are utilities,
tools, applications, or libraries that form or support the foundation of the
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core repositories are all those located under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative&#34;&gt;github.com/knative organization&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-repository-requirements&#34;&gt;Core Repository Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repository must live under github.com/knative/project-name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must adopt the Knative Code of Conduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All code projects must use the Apache License version 2.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation repositories must use Creative Commons License version 4.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All OWNERS must be members of the Knative community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repository creation must be approved by the Technical Oversight Committee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements-for-repository-donation&#34;&gt;Requirements for Repository Donation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Technical Oversight Committee may allow repositories to be donated to the
Knative project. In &lt;em&gt;addition&lt;/em&gt; to meeting the core repository requirements,
donated repositories must:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopt the Google CLA bot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All contributors to the donated repository must have signed the Google CLA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All code must adopt the standard Knative header, attributing copyright as
follows: &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Copyright &amp;lt;year&amp;gt; The Knative Authors&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additions of the standard Knative header to code created by the contributors
can occur post-transfer, but should ideally occur shortly thereafter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;code&gt;AUTHORS&lt;/code&gt; file should be created in the repo root, if one does not already
exist, that includes the original authors of the code. See
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving/blob/main/AUTHORS&#34;&gt;knative/serving AUTHORS&lt;/a&gt;
for reference.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that copyright notices should only be modified or removed by the people
or organizations named in the notice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;removing-repositories&#34;&gt;Removing Repositories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As important as it is to add new repositories, it is equally important to prune
repositories when necessary. See &lt;a href=&#34;#grounds-for-removal&#34;&gt;Grounds for removal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to the success of Knative that all Knative repositories stay
active, healthy, and aligned with the scope and mission of project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;grounds-for-removal&#34;&gt;Grounds for removal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core repositories may be removed from the project if they are deemed &lt;em&gt;inactive&lt;/em&gt;.
Inactive repositories are those that meet any of the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no longer any active maintainers for the project, and no
replacements can be found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All PRs and issues have gone un-addressed for longer than six months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There have been no new commits or other changes in more than a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The contents have been folded into another actively maintained project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;procedure-for-removal&#34;&gt;Procedure for removal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a repository has been deemed eligible for removal, we take the following
steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A proposal to remove the repository is brought to the attention of the
Technical Oversight Committee through a GitHub issue posted in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/community&#34;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; repo.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback is encouraged during a Technical Oversight Committee meeting before
any action is taken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the TOC has approved of the removal, if the repo is not moving to another
actively maintained project:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The repo description is edited to start with the phrase &amp;ldquo;[EOL]&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All open issues and PRs are closed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All external collaborates are removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All webhooks, apps, integrations, or services are removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub pages are disabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The repo is marked as archived using GitHub&amp;rsquo;s archive feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The removal is announced on the knative-dev mailing list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This procedure maintains the complete record of issues, PRs, and other
contributions. It leaves the repository read-only and makes it clear that the
repository is retired and no longer maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional--experimental-repositories&#34;&gt;Additional / Experimental Repositories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is beneficial for Knative working groups to be able to own code outside the
core &lt;code&gt;knative&lt;/code&gt; organization, which is kept intentionally small and has a high
bar for entry.  The &lt;code&gt;knative-sandbox&lt;/code&gt; GitHub organization was created for this
purpose.  Repositories in &lt;code&gt;knative-sandbox&lt;/code&gt; are intended to give working groups
more latitude to experiment with new ideas and to self-organize and manage
contributions which may be important to the project but which do not need the
level of governance of the core project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;code&gt;knative-sandbox&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; an incubation area for projects entering
the &lt;code&gt;knative&lt;/code&gt; github org; in most cases, projects in the sandbox will remain
there for the entire duration. &lt;code&gt;knative-sandbox&lt;/code&gt; also provides a location for
implementations of core interfaces which do not themselves need to be part of
every knative installation, such as networking or eventing integrations. In the
event that a working group wants a project in sandbox to be considered for
transfer to the &lt;code&gt;knative&lt;/code&gt; org, the request will be considered on a case-by-case
basis by joint decision of the Steering Committee and the Technical Oversight
Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mechanics-of-working-group-owned-repositories-in-knative-sandbox&#34;&gt;Mechanics of working-group owned repositories in &lt;code&gt;knative-sandbox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;creation&#34;&gt;Creation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: prior art here from the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/community/blob/master/github-management/kubernetes-repositories.md&#34;&gt;Kubernetes community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working groups are allowed to request repositories that meet the following
requirements. The Steering Committee and TOC will maintain the process and
perform the repository creation steps to ensure that the following requirements
have been met:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vendor dependencies must be clearly called out, and participation must be open
to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the repository is for integration with a specific technology vendor,
affiliation with that vendor must not be required for participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-integration repositories should aim to avoid dependencies on
vendor-specific technology by publishing abstract interfaces which can be
implemented by multiple vendors. Those implementations are not required to
live in separate repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must adopt the Knative CLA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must adopt the Knative
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/community/blob/main/CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must adopt the Apache 2.0 license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must be sponsored by a specific working group, which should be designated in
the &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; for the repo. In addition, at least one WG lead must be in the
root-level OWNERS file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright assigned to The Knative Authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document clear release and install processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly document the stability and API guarantees (both in the top-level
&lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; and by using appropriate API versioning for Kubernetes apigroups).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The TOC will maintain a template which will be used during the creation of
new repositories. Existing repositiories are encouraged to update their
&lt;code&gt;README&lt;/code&gt;s from time to time as the format changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes APIs must be homed in a valid group with a DNS prefix approved by
the Steering Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APIs under &lt;code&gt;knative.dev&lt;/code&gt; should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be under a subdomain managed by the owning Working Group (e.g.
&lt;code&gt;sources.knative.dev&lt;/code&gt;, not &lt;code&gt;knative.dev&lt;/code&gt;). The TOC is considered the
authority for assigning subdomains to working groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coordinate with the Working Group in API naming to avoid collisions or
confusing naming. This also includes API review by the responsible
Working Group to ensure consistency and alignment with duck-type field
naming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working groups must designate the repositories they own (by prefix or in the README.md of the repo, at a minimum).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repositories owned by working groups are encouraged to embrace the project value
of pluggability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;non-requirements&#34;&gt;Non-requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are not required to create a working-group-owned repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steering or Trademark approval (see &lt;a href=&#34;#the-fine-print&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;the fine print&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TOC approval
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TOC may request certain naming patterns (e.g. &lt;code&gt;kn-plugin&lt;/code&gt; for client WG)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solving an unique problem (exploring different approaches to problems outside
the core is actively encouraged!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-fine-print&#34;&gt;The fine print&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steering and Trademark reserve the right to require that repos be removed or
transferred out of the &lt;code&gt;knative-sandbox&lt;/code&gt; organization and API groups to be
renamed. This is intended to simplify the process in the common case, while
giving Steering or Trademark the ability to step in and rectify problems that
may arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deletion&#34;&gt;Deletion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working groups are responsible for the upkeep of their repositories and are
expected to keep a high quality bar. Inactive or non-conforming repositories
should be archived, deleted, or moved out of the &lt;code&gt;knative-sandbox&lt;/code&gt; organization,
following the general &lt;a href=&#34;#procedure-for-removal&#34;&gt;Procedure for Removal&lt;/a&gt; for
repositories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contents of this page are adopted from the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/community/blob/master/github-management/kubernetes-repositories.md&#34;&gt;Kubernetes repository guidelines&lt;/a&gt;,
which is licensed under Apache License 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative technical oversight committee</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/tech-oversight-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/tech-oversight-committee/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Knative Technical Oversight Committee (TOC) is responsible for cross-cutting
product and design decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#charter&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#committee-mechanics&#34;&gt;Committee Mechanics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#committee-meeting&#34;&gt;Committee Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#committee-members&#34;&gt;Committee Members&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charter&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical Project Oversight, Direction &amp;amp; Delivery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set the overall technical direction and roadmap of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolve technical issues, technical disagreements and escalations within the
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set the priorities of individual releases to ensure coherency and proper
sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approve declaring a new long-term supported (LTS) Knative release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approve the creation and dissolution of working groups and approve
leadership changes of working groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create proposals based on TOC discussions and bring them to the relevant
working groups for discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approve the creation/deletion of GitHub repositories, along with other
high-level administrative issues around GitHub and our other tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Healthy Community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establish and maintain the overall technical governance guidelines for the
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decide which sub-projects are part of the Knative project, including
accepting new sub-projects and pruning existing sub-projects to maintain
community focus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure the team adheres to our
&lt;a href=&#34;./CONTRIBUTING.md#code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; and respects our
&lt;a href=&#34;./VALUES.md&#34;&gt;values&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foster an environment for a healthy and happy community of developers and
contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;committee-mechanics&#34;&gt;Committee Mechanics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TOC is &lt;a href=&#34;./mechanics/TOC.md&#34;&gt;elected by the community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TOC’s work includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular committee meetings to discuss hot topics, resulting in a set of
published
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1LzOUbTMkMEsCRfwjYm5TKZUWfyXpO589-r9K2rXlHfk/edit&#34;&gt;meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create, review, approve and publish technical project governance documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create proposals for consideration by individual working groups to help steer
their work towards a common project-wide objective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review/address/comment on project issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Act as a high-level sounding board for technical questions or designs bubbled
up by the working groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;committee-meeting&#34;&gt;Committee Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community members are encouraged to suggest topics for discussion ahead of the
TOC meetings, and are invited to observe these meetings and engage with the TOC
during the community feedback period at the end of each meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Artifact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Google Group&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-tech-oversight&#34;&gt;knative-tech-oversight@googlegroups.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting VC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1LzOUbTMkMEsCRfwjYm5TKZUWfyXpO589-r9K2rXlHfk/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Community Meeting Calendar&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thursdays at 11:30a-12p &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://calendar.google.com/calendar/embed?src=knative.team_9q83bg07qs5b9rrslp5jor4l6s%40group.calendar.google.com&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meeting Notes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1LzOUbTMkMEsCRfwjYm5TKZUWfyXpO589-r9K2rXlHfk/edit&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Document Folder&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/13-h81zualjRSNkCSFItODfk-NZ7dkMut&#34;&gt;Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;committee-members&#34;&gt;Committee Members&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current members of the TOC are shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Member&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Term Start&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Term End&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/evankanderson.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Evan Anderson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/evankanderson&#34;&gt;@evankanderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/markusthoemmes.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Markus Thömmes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/markusthoemmes&#34;&gt;@markusthoemmes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020-06-09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/rhuss.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Roland Huß&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rhuss&#34;&gt;@rhuss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021-02-16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative steering committee</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/steering-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/steering-committee/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Knative Steering Committee (KSC) is
&lt;a href=&#34;./GOVERNANCE.md&#34;&gt;responsible for the general health of the Knative community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The governance of Knative is an open, living document, and will continue to
evolve as the community and project change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#charter&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#delegated-authority&#34;&gt;Delegated authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#committee-meetings&#34;&gt;Committee Meetings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#committee-members&#34;&gt;Committee Members&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#decision-process&#34;&gt;Decision process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#getting-in-touch&#34;&gt;Getting in touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#election-procedure&#34;&gt;Elections&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#timeline&#34;&gt;Timeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#election-officers&#34;&gt;Election Officer(s)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#eligibility-to-vote&#34;&gt;Eligibility to Vote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#candidate-eligibility&#34;&gt;Candidate Eligibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#voting-procedure&#34;&gt;Voting Procedure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#limitations-on-company-representation&#34;&gt;Limitations on Company Representation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#vacancies&#34;&gt;Vacancies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#transition&#34;&gt;Transition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#changes-to-the-charter&#34;&gt;Changes to the charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#authority-facilitation-and-decision-making-in-knative&#34;&gt;Authority, Facilitation, and Decision Making in Knative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charter&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define, evolve, and promote the vision, values, and mission of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define and evolve project governance structures and policies, including
project roles and how collaborators become members, approvers, leads, and/or
administrators. This includes policy for the creation and administration of
&lt;a href=&#34;./working-groups/WORKING-GROUPS.md&#34;&gt;working groups&lt;/a&gt; and committees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steward, control access, delegate access, and establish processes regarding
all Knative project resources and has the final say in the disposition of
those resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advise the Trademark Committee on usage of the brand and marks in relation to
promoting the community. This advice is non-binding on the Trademark
Committee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define and evolve the scope of the Knative community and extensions, and the
process for migration of sandbox projects into Knative Extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receive and handle reports about &lt;a href=&#34;./CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;
violations and maintain confidentiality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Receive security reports; work with the appropriate technical leads to accept
or reject the report; maintain the private nature of such reports until
disclosed to the broader community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act as the final escalation point and decider for any disputes, issues,
clarifications, or escalations within the project scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;delegated-authority&#34;&gt;Delegated authority&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KSC may choose to delegate its authority to other committees as-needed. The
committee currently recognizes this delegated authority for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical guidance is delegated to the
&lt;a href=&#34;./TECH-OVERSIGHT-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;Technical Oversight Committee&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;committee-meetings&#34;&gt;Committee Meetings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KSC currently meets weekly, or as-needed. Meetings are open to public and held
online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the private nature of some of these discussions (e.g. privacy, private
emails to the committee, code of conduct violations, escalations, disputes
between members, security reports, etc.) some meetings are held in private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/16Rpd2nhmLWrkFJUfpJ31Ox2PpultJ-bYIhqaiWQff_I/edit&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt;
are available to members of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev mailing list&lt;/a&gt;
(note: these are accessible to members of the knative-users list as well).
Public meetings will be recorded and the recordings made available publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions and proposals for changes to governance are posted as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/community/issues&#34;&gt;issues in the community repo&lt;/a&gt;, and
the KSC invites your feedback there. See &lt;a href=&#34;#getting-in-touch&#34;&gt;Getting in touch&lt;/a&gt;
for other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;committee-members&#34;&gt;Committee members&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seats on the Steering Committee are held by an individual, not by their
employer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current membership of the committee is currently (listed alphabetically by
first name):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Member&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Organization&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Term Start&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Term End&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/thisisnotapril.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April Kyle Nassi&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thisisnotapril&#34;&gt;@thisisnotapril&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/bsnchan.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brenda Chan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bsnchan&#34;&gt;@bsnchan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/mbehrendt.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Michael Behrendt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IBM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mbehrendt&#34;&gt;@mbehrendt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/pmorie.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paul Morie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red Hat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pmorie&#34;&gt;@pmorie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020-12-11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/vaikas.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ville Aikas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vaikas&#34;&gt;@vaikas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020-12-11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decision-process&#34;&gt;Decision process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steering committee desires to always reach consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisions requiring a vote include: issuing written policy, amending existing
written policy, creating, removing, or modifying a working group, all spending,
hiring, and contracting, official responses to publicly raised issues, or any
other decisions that at least half the members present decide require a vote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisions are made in meetings when a quorum of the members are present and may
pass with at least half the members of the committee supporting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quorum is considered reached when at least half of the members are present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-in-touch&#34;&gt;Getting in touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to raise issues to the steering committee for decision:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emailing the steering committee at
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:steering@knative.team&#34;&gt;steering@knative.team&lt;/a&gt;.
This is a private discussion list to which all members of the committee have
access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open an issue on a knative repository and indicate that you would like
attention from the steering committee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;composition&#34;&gt;Composition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steering committee has 5 seats. These five seats are Contributing seats,
open to any project contributor. In the future, the steering committe would like
to add two End-User seats, open only to active end-user community members, once
the selection criteria have been established. See
&lt;a href=&#34;#candidate-eligibility&#34;&gt;candidate eligibility&lt;/a&gt; for definitions of these
categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steering Committee members serve for 2-year terms, staggered in order to
preserve continuity. Every year either two or three contributor seats are
elected. Once end-user mechanics are established, one end user seat would be
elected on the same schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;election-procedure&#34;&gt;Election Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;timeline&#34;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steering Committee elections are held annually. Six weeks or more before the
election, the Steering Committee will appoint Election Officer(s) (see below).
Four weeks or more before the election, the Election Officer(s) will issue a
call for nominations, publish the list of voters, and open the call for
exceptions. One week before the election the call for nominations and exceptions
will be closed. The election will be open for voting not less than two weeks and
not more than four. The results of the election will be announced within one
week of closing the election. New Steering Committee members will take office on
December 1 of each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;election-officers&#34;&gt;Election Officer(s)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six weeks or more before the election, the Steering Committee will appoint
between one and three Election Officer(s) to administer the election. Elections
Officers will be Knative community members in good standing who are eligible to
vote, are not running for Steering in that election, who are not currently part
of the Steering Committee and can make a public promise of impartiality. They
will be responsible for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making all announcements associated with the election&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparing and distributing electronic ballots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Judging exception requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting candidates in preparing and sharing statements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tallying voting results according to the rules in this charter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eligibility-to-vote&#34;&gt;Eligibility to Vote&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has at least 50 contributions in the last 12 months is eligible to
vote in the Steering election. Contributions are defined as opening PRs,
reviewing and commenting on PRs, opening and commenting on issues, writing
design docs, commenting on design docs, helping people on slack, participating
in working groups, and other efforts that help advance Knative the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://knative.teststats.cncf.io/d/9/developer-activity-counts-by-repository-group-table?orgId=1&amp;amp;var-period_name=Last%20year&#34;&gt;This dashboard&lt;/a&gt;
shows only GitHub based contributions and does not capture all the contributions
we value. We expect this metric not to capture everyone who should be eligible
to vote. If a community member has had significant contributions over the past
year but is not captured in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://knative.teststats.cncf.io/d/9/developer-activity-counts-by-repository-group-table?orgId=1&amp;amp;var-period_name=Last%20year&#34;&gt;stats.knative.dev dashboard&lt;/a&gt;,
they will be able to submit an exception form to the Elections Officer(s) who
will then review and determine whether this member should be eligible to vote.
All exceptions, and the reasons for them, will be recorded in a log that will be
available to Steering and the TOC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electoral roll of all eligible voters will be captured at
knative/community/steering-elections/$YEAR/voters.md and the voters’ guide will
be captured at knative/community/steering-elections/$YEAR/README.md,
similar to the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/steering/blob/master/elections.md&#34;&gt;kubernetes election process&lt;/a&gt;
and identical to the TOC election process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are committed to an inclusive process and will adapt future eligibility
requirements based on community feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;candidate-eligibility&#34;&gt;Candidate Eligibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community members must be eligible to vote in order to stand for election (this
includes voters who qualify for an exception). Candidates may self-nominate or
be nominated by another eligible member. There are no term limits for KSC
members. Nothing prevents a qualified member from serving on both the TOC and SC
simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To run for a Contributing seat, a candidate must additionally be at least a
project Member as defined in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/community/blob/main/ROLES.md&#34;&gt;ROLES.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End-user seats are planned to enable employees of organizations which use but do
not sell Knative-derived products. The mechanics of eligibility for end-user
seats are still in progress; it is expected that end-user seats will add to the
current Steering options to specific include end-user perspectives in the
decision-making process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;voting-procedure&#34;&gt;Voting Procedure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elections will be held using a time-limited
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Condorcet_method&#34;&gt;Condorcet&lt;/a&gt; ranking on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://civs.cs.cornell.edu/&#34;&gt;CIVS&lt;/a&gt; using the Schulze method. The top
vote-getters will be elected to the open seats, with the exceptions for company
representation discussed below. This is the same process used for TOC elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;limitations-on-company-representation&#34;&gt;Limitations on Company Representation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more than two seats may be held by employees of the same organization (or
conglomerate, in the case of companies owning each other). Additionally, each
End-User seat (when available) must belong to an employee from a different
organization. If the results of an election result in greater than two employees
of the same organization, the lowest vote getters from any particular employer
will be removed until representation on the committee is down to two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If employers change because of job changes, acquisitions, or other events, in a
way that would yield more than 2 seats being held by employees of the same
organization, sufficient members of the committee must resign until only two
employees of the same employer are left. If it is impossible to find sufficient
members to resign, all employees of that organization will be removed and new
special elections held. In the event of a question of company membership (for
example evaluating independence of corporate subsidiaries) a majority of all
non-involved Steering Committee members will decide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vacancies&#34;&gt;Vacancies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the event of a resignation or other loss of an elected SC member, the
candidate with the next most votes from the previous election will be offered
the seat, provided that person otherwise qualifies to join the SC. This process
will continue until the seat is filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case this fails to fill the seat, a special election for that position will
be held as soon as possible, unless the regular SC election is less than 7 weeks
away. Eligible voters from the most recent election will vote in the special
election. Eligibility will not be redetermined at the time of the special
election. Any replacement SC member will serve out the remainder of the term for
the person they are replacing, regardless of the length of that remainder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transition&#34;&gt;Transition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to transition from the original, organization-appointed Steering
Committee structure (the &amp;ldquo;bootstrap&amp;rdquo; committee), elections will be phased in
over 14 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 2020, two positions will be elected, including two Contributing
seats and zero End-User seats (because end-user seat mechanics are still being
worked out). One Google, one IBM/RedHat, and one VMware seat will be retained
from the current Steering Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October or November 2021, the three remaining &amp;ldquo;bootstrap SC&amp;rdquo; seats will be
replaced by elected seats (three Contributing and hopefully one End-User seat).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-to-the-charter&#34;&gt;Changes to the charter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes to the KSC charter may be proposed via a PR on the charter itself.
Amendments are accepted with majority consent of the committee as per the
&lt;a href=&#34;#decision-process&#34;&gt;decision process&lt;/a&gt; outlined above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposals and amendments to the charter are available for at least a period of
one week for comments and questions before a vote will occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;authority-facilitation-and-decision-making-in-knative&#34;&gt;Authority, Facilitation, and Decision Making in Knative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally most decisions will be made at the lowest possible level within the
project: within individual working groups. When this is not possible for
technical decisions, the TOC can help facilitate a conversation to work through
the contended issue. When facilitation by the TOC does not resolve the contended
issue, the Steering Committee can help facilitate. When facilitation by the SC
does not resolve the contention, the SC may have to make a decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if the SC is called to resolve contended decisions regularly, it is a
symptom of a larger problem in the community that will need to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portions of this document are adapted from the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/istio/community/blob/master/STEERING-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;Istio Steering Committee&lt;/a&gt;
documentation, and other portions are copied from the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/steering/blob/master/elections.md&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Steering Committee&lt;/a&gt;,
both of which are licensed under the Apache License 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Slack guidelines</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/slack-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/slack-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Slack is the main communication platform for Knative outside of our mailing
lists. It’s important that conversation stays on topic in each channel, and that
everyone abides by the &lt;a href=&#34;./CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. Community
members should all expect to have a positive experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chat is searchable and public. Do not make comments that you would not say on a
video recording or in another public space. Please be courteous to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@here&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;@channel&lt;/code&gt; should be used rarely. Members will receive notifications
from these commands and we are a global project - please be kind. Note: &lt;code&gt;@all&lt;/code&gt;
is only to be used by admins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev&#34;&gt;Knative Slack&lt;/a&gt; instance at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.knative.dev&#34;&gt;https://slack.knative.dev&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knative &lt;a href=&#34;./CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; applies throughout the
project, and includes all communication mediums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;admins&#34;&gt;Admins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members of the
&lt;a href=&#34;TECH-OVERSIGHT-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;Technical Oversight Committee (TOC)&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;STEERING-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;Knative Steering Committee (KSC)&lt;/a&gt; are also the
administrators for the Knative Slack instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack admins should make sure to mention this in the “What I do” section of
their Slack profile, as well as for which time zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To connect: please reach out in the #slack-admins channel or DM (Direct Message)
a member of the &lt;a href=&#34;STEERING-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;KSC&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&#34;TECH-OVERSIGHT-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;TOC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;admin-expectations-and-guidelines&#34;&gt;Admin expectations and guidelines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adhere to Code of Conduct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take care of spam as soon as possible, which may mean taking action by making
members inactive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moderating and fostering a safe environment for conversations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring Code of Conduct issues to the Steering Committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create relevant channels and list Code of Conduct in new channel welcome
message&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help troubleshoot Slack issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review bot, token, and webhook requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be helpful!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-channels&#34;&gt;Creating channels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please reach out to the #slack-admins group with your request to create a new
channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channels are dedicated to &lt;a href=&#34;./working-groups/WORKING-GROUPS.md&#34;&gt;Working Groups&lt;/a&gt;,
sub-projects, community topics, and related programs/projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channels are not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;company specific; e.g. a channel named for a cloud provider must be used for
conversation about Knative-related topics on that cloud, and not proprietary
information of the provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;private unless there is an exception: code of conduct matters, mentoring,
security/vulnerabilities, or steering committee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All channels need a documented purpose. Use this space to welcome the targeted
community: promote your meetings, post agendas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may make special accommodations where necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;escalating-andor-reporting-a-problem&#34;&gt;Escalating and/or reporting a problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the #slack-admins channel or contact one of the admins in the closest
timezone via DM directly and describe the situation. If the issue can be
documented, please take a screenshot to include in your message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-if-you-have-a-problem-with-an-admin&#34;&gt;What if you have a problem with an admin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send a DM to another listed Admin and describe the situation, or if it’s a code
of conduct issue, please send an email to
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:knative-code-of-conduct@googlegroups.com&#34;&gt;knative-code-of-conduct@googlegroups.com&lt;/a&gt; and describe the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bots-tokens-and-webhooks&#34;&gt;Bots, tokens, and webhooks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bots, tokens, and webhooks are reviewed on a case-by-case basis. Expect most
requests will be rejected due to security, privacy, and usability concerns. Bots
and the like tend to make a lot of noise in channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join #slack-admins and have a discussion about your request before
requesting the access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;admin-moderation&#34;&gt;Admin moderation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be mindful of how you handle communication during stressful interactions.
Administrators act as direct representatives of the project, and need to
maintain a very high level of professionalism at all times. If you feel too
involved in the situation to maintain impartiality or professionalism, that’s a
great time to enlist the help of another admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to take any situations that involve upset or angry members to DM or video
chat. Please document these interactions for other Slack admins to review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content will be automatically removed if it violates code of conduct or is a
sales pitch. Admins will take a screenshot of such behavior in order to document
the situation. Google takes such violations extremely seriously, and they will
be handled swiftly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deactivating-accounts&#34;&gt;Deactivating accounts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For reasons listed below, admins may deactivate individual Slack accounts. Due
to Slack’s framework, it does not allow for an account to be banned or suspended
in the traditional sense.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://get.Slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/204475027-Deactivate-a-member-s-account&#34;&gt;Read Slack’s policy on this.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spreading spam content in DMs or channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not adhering to the &lt;a href=&#34;./CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; in DMs or channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overtly selling products, related or unrelated to Knative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;specific-channel-rules&#34;&gt;Specific channel rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case that certain channels have rules or guidelines, they will be listed
in the purpose or pinned docs of that channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threaded-conversations&#34;&gt;Threaded Conversations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack threads in public channels are extremely useful for quickly and openly collaborating with your fellow contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, while Slack threads are good for quick discussion, they serve as a poor record of decisions. Discoverability and searchability of threads isn&amp;rsquo;t nearly as good as alternatives (see below), particularly for contributors arriving weeks or months later. For this reason it&amp;rsquo;s important that Slack discussions make their way to less ephemeral and more comprehensive artifacts for sharing ideas and proposals with the wider community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These artifacts include, but are not limited to: Github Issues + Pull Requests, Github Discussions, Google Docs, or Mailing List posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a general rule-of-thumb: if your Slack thread reaches more than 40 messages, ask yourself &amp;ldquo;If I weren&amp;rsquo;t in this thread, would it be important for me to know the contents of this conversation?&amp;rdquo; If the answer is yes, it may be time to end the discussion and create one of the artifacts listed above to encourage slower and more deliberate discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dm-direct-message-conversations&#34;&gt;DM (Direct Message) conversations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do not engage in proprietary company specific conversations in the
Knative Slack instance. This is meant for conversations related to Knative open
source topics and community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proprietary conversations should occur in your company communication platforms.
As with all communication, please be mindful of appropriateness,
professionalism, and applicability to the Knative community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative project values</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/values/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;knative-community-values&#34;&gt;Knative Community Values&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to have explicitly defined values, these are ours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We welcome all skill sets&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Knative community should strive to be approachable, welcoming, and
friendly to new contributors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;All contributions are recognized&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A successful project requires contributions of many different kinds, from
code to program management to customer research. As a community we want
status within the project to be derived from contributions to the project
recognizing that all contribution types have value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roles and skills should be aligned so contributors feel empowered to lead.
If someone is doing the work, the role should be codified / formalized; eg
glue, release, notes, PM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership roles should be earned by individuals based on their
contributions in the project over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We value transparency and visibility&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision making should be as transparent as possible at each level in the
project:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work and decisions should happen in public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All contributors should follow the same process, regardless of their
employer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be public notes and meeting recordings so that anyone can
follow discussion regardless of their timezone or ability to meet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Focus on what is right for the users (&amp;ldquo;delight our users&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We should be wearing community hats in the community; community over company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on what’s right for the users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We welcome structured, customer-driven features (end-users, PM roles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;We value feedback&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be well-defined, visible, accountable feedback loops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative team values</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/team-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/team-values/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;We want to make sure every member has a shared understanding of the goals and
values we hold as a team:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimize for the &lt;strong&gt;overall project&lt;/strong&gt;, not your own area or feature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A shortcut for one individual can mean a lot of extra work or disruption for
the rest of the team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our repos should always be in release shape: &lt;strong&gt;Always Green&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This lets us move faster in the mid and long term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This implies investments in build/test infrastructure to have fast, reliable
tests to ensure that we can release at any time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra discipline may require more work by individuals to keep the build in
good state, but less work overall for the team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be &lt;strong&gt;specific&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;respectful&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;courteous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disagreements are welcome and encouraged, but don&amp;rsquo;t use broad
generalizations, exaggerations, or judgment words that can be taken
personally. Consider other people’s perspective (including the wide range of
applicability of Knative). Empathize with our users. Focus on the specific
issue at hand, and remember that we all care about the project, first and
foremost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emails to the &lt;a href=&#34;./CONTRIBUTING.md#contributing-a-feature&#34;&gt;mailing lists&lt;/a&gt;,
document comments, or meetings are often better and higher bandwidth ways to
communicate complex and nuanced design issues, as opposed to protracted
heated live chats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be mindful of the terminology you are using, it may not be the same as
someone else and cause misunderstanding. To promote clear and precise
communication, define the terms you are using in context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See also the &lt;a href=&#34;./CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;, which everyone must
abide by.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raising issues is great, suggesting solutions is even better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think of a proposed alternative and improvement rather than just what you
perceive as wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have no immediate solution even after thinking about it - if
something does seem significant, raise it to someone who might be able to
also think of solutions or to the group (don’t stay frustrated! Feel safe in
bringing up issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid rehashing old issues that have been resolved/decided (unless you have
new insights or information).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be productive and &lt;strong&gt;happy&lt;/strong&gt;, and most importantly, have &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative Trademark committee</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/trademark-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/trademark-committee/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The Knative Trademark Committee (KTC)
&lt;a href=&#34;./GOVERNANCE.md&#34;&gt;advises the trademark owner on the usage and enforcement of Knative logos, names, and trademarks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a separate body from the &lt;a href=&#34;./STEERING-COMMITTEE.md&#34;&gt;Steering Committee&lt;/a&gt; to
better represent the needs of vendors and other companies which market products
in conjunction with the Knative mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The governance of Knative is an open, living document, and will continue to
evolve as the community and project change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#charter&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#delegated-authority&#34;&gt;Delegated Authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#committee-meetings&#34;&gt;Committee Meetings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#committee-members&#34;&gt;Committee Members&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#decision-process&#34;&gt;Decision Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#getting-in-touch&#34;&gt;Getting in touch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#composition&#34;&gt;Composition&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#maintaining-the-trademark-committee&#34;&gt;Maintaining the Trademark Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charter&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advise the Trademark owner on the definition and enforcement of the &amp;ldquo;Knative&amp;rdquo;
trademark usage and branding guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review and approve conformance rules and tests that define brand use
decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review and approve the scope and definition of additional derivative Knative
marks (e.g. Knative Serving, Knative Core, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only the Trademark Committee can redefine its own charter, membership, and
authority over Knative Trademark, conformance, and brand decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;delegated-authority&#34;&gt;Delegated authority&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trademark Committee may choose to create and delegate its authority to other
committees as-needed. This may be used (for example) to create sub-committees
for specific technical or marketing questions related to conformance or joint
marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trademark Committee may delegate enforcement authority for one or more marks
to other Knative committees (such as the steering committee) to provide branding
for nascent efforts which are not yet subject to conformance and third-party
licensing. This delegation may be further delegated transitively, as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is expected that the Trademark Committee will delegate one or more marks to
the steering committee to provide branding for nascent efforts which are not yet
subject to conformance and third-party licensing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;committee-meetings&#34;&gt;Committee Meetings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trademark committee currently meets weekly, or as-needed. Meetings are open to public and held online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the private nature of some of these discussions (e.g. trade secrets, legal
and compliance concerns, etc.) some meetings may be held in private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1ghGQl0O7TM8N_YQ33w6xKyQ2yUnOX0ACsOnlqoV_XgY/edit#&#34;&gt;Meeting notes&lt;/a&gt; are available to members of the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev mailing list&lt;/a&gt;
(note: these are accessible to members of the knative-users list as well).
Public meetings will be recorded and the recordings made available publicly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions and proposals for changes to governance are posted as
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/community/issues&#34;&gt;issues in the community repo&lt;/a&gt;, and
the trademark committee invites your feedback there. See
&lt;a href=&#34;#getting-in-touch&#34;&gt;Getting in touch&lt;/a&gt; for other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;committee-members&#34;&gt;Committee Members&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Member&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Organization&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Profile&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ron Avnur&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Google&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ronavn&#34;&gt;@ronavn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Doug Davis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;IBM/RedHat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/duglin&#34;&gt;@duglin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brenda Chan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bsnchan&#34;&gt;@bsnchan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Committee members for bootstrap term will be chosen during the Steering
Committee election process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decision-process&#34;&gt;Decision process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trademark Committee desires to always reach consensus. Additionally, each
member can veto decisions regarding assignment of the mark, charter,
conformance, and scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisions requiring a vote include: issuing written policy, amending existing
written policy, official responses to publicly raised issues, or any other
decisions that are in the scope of the Trademark Committee’s charter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voted decisions pass when all members vote to approve the decision, or a
majority approves and the rest of the members abstain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decisions are made in meetings when a quorum of the members are present and may
pass with at least half the members of the committee supporting it. Vetoes by
absent committee members must be presented within 5 business days of a published
decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quorum is considered reached when at least half of the members are present.
Quorum may be established over email or electronic chat systems as well as via
video or in-person meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case of extended absence or removal from the project for a code of conduct
violation, the organization of the absent member may appoint a single
replacement delegate from the same company during the absence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-in-touch&#34;&gt;Getting in touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three ways to raise issues to the steering committee for decision:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emailing the steering committee at
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:trademark@knative.team&#34;&gt;trademark@knative.team&lt;/a&gt;.
This is a private discussion list to which all members of the committee have
access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open an issue in the knative community repository and indicate that you would like
attention from the trademark committee by using the &amp;lsquo;trademark&amp;rsquo; label, or by
tagging the trademark committee GitHub user group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat with the trademark committee in the #trademark-questions Slack channel
on the Knative Slack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;composition&#34;&gt;Composition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trademark Committee is composed of company representatives from companies
which have substantially contributed to Knative over the last year, as well as
the trademark holder. Companies which have a currently-unfilled seat on the
Trademark Committee may veto decisions made in the 5 business days prior to the
selection of the representative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company representatives serving on the Trademark Committee may individually
resign or be removed from their seats by their affiliated company with at least
5 days notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 2020 year, one seat is assigned to each of Google, IBM/RedHat, and
VMware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;maintaining-the-trademark-committee&#34;&gt;Maintaining the Trademark Committee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trademark Committee membership is refreshed annually on the same timeline as
the Steering Committee elections (during the month of October). The Trademark
Committee&amp;rsquo;s size is unbounded and may grow or shrink depending on the activity
in the project in the year prior to each refresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Membership in the committee is determined by counting the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://knative.teststats.cncf.io/d/5/companies-table?orgId=1&amp;amp;var-period_name=Last%20year&amp;amp;var-metric=contributions&#34;&gt;easily countable contributions over the last year&lt;/a&gt;.
Each company which has contributed at least 15% of the total project
contributions will be eligible to select one representative to the committee.
Not all contributions are easy to count and many significant contributions are
hard to count. Vendors may petition the Trademark Committee to articulate why
they should receive additional contribution credit towards membership on the
Trademark Committee. Corporate parents, affiliates, or subsidiaries shall be
counted as one company.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Knative community roles</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/roles/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;This document describes the set of roles individuals might have within the
Knative community, the requirements of each role, and the privileges that each
role grants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#role-summary&#34;&gt;Role Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#member&#34;&gt;Member&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#approver&#34;&gt;Approver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#working-group-technical-lead&#34;&gt;Working Group Technical Lead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#working-group-execution-lead&#34;&gt;Working Group Execution Lead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#scribe&#34;&gt;Scribe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;#notes&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; on roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;role-summary&#34;&gt;Role Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table lists the roles we use within the Knative community. The
table describes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General responsibilities expected by individuals in each role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requirements necessary to join or stay in a given role for repos in the Knative GitHub org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the role manifests in terms of permissions and privileges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Role&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Requirements&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Privileges&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Scope&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Member&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Regular active contributor in the community&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Has made multiple contributions to the project&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Member of the GitHub Knative org&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Member of the Knative Slack workspace&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Edit access to team drive&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;GitHub Organization&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Approver&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Approve contributions from other members&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Highly experienced and active reviewer and contributor to an area&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Entry in one or more OWNERS files in GitHub, and write permissions
        on one or more repos allowing PRs to be merged
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;GitHub Directory&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Working Group Technical Lead&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Set priorities for a functional area and approve proposals&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Triage incoming issues, set milestones, repo labels&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Roadmap alignment with top-level backlog&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mentor new contributors, project members, and approvers&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Succession - identifying next steps for members of the working group&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Responsible for technical health of their functional area&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Sponsored by the technical oversight committee as documented
        &lt;a href=&#34;./mechanics/WORKING-GROUP-PROCESSES.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Write permissions on one or more repos allowing issues to be manipulated&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Working Group&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Working Group Execution Lead&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Run their working group: Meetings, notes, roadmap, report&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Responsible for the holistic health of the &lt;i&gt;working group&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Work organization, planning, high-level execution&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Triage incoming issues, set milestones, repo labels&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ensure all required skills are present within the working group&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mentor new contributors, project members, and approvers&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Sponsored by the technical oversight committee as documented
        &lt;a href=&#34;./mechanics/WORKING-GROUP-PROCESSES.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Write permissions on one or more repos allowing issues to be manipulated&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Working Group&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Scribe&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ensure important information is represented in working group notes&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Post WG recordings to team drive&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Sponsored by a working group execution or technical lead.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Write permissions to team drive and team calendar&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Working Group&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that repos in the knative-sandbox GitHub org are a reflection of the WG leads. These leads are free to use their judgement to set the bar for what is required to become an approver and/or owner for knative-sandbox repos they are responsible for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;member&#34;&gt;Member&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Established community members are expected to demonstrate their adherence to the
principles in this document, familiarity with project organization, roles,
policies, procedures, conventions, etc., and technical and/or writing ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members are continuously active contributors in the community. They can have
issues and PRs assigned to them, participate in working group meetings, and
pre-submit tests are automatically run for their PRs. Members are expected to
remain active contributors to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All members are encouraged to help with the code review burden, although each PR
must be reviewed by an official &lt;a href=&#34;#approver&#34;&gt;Approver&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reviewing, members should focus on code quality and correctness, including
testing and factoring. Members might also review for more holistic issues, but
this is not a requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Member of the Knative github org. Create a PR adding you to
&lt;a href=&#34;../peribolos/knative.yaml&#34;&gt;knative.yaml&lt;/a&gt; and/or to
&lt;a href=&#34;../peribolos/knative-sandbox.yaml&#34;&gt;knative-sandbox.yaml&lt;/a&gt; which after when
merged will send you an invite that you have to accept to become a member
of these organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has made multiple contributions to the project or community. Contributions
might include, but are not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authoring and reviewing PRs on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filing and commenting on issues on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributing to working group or community discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscribed to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/knative-dev&#34;&gt;knative-dev@googlegroups.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actively contributing to 1 or more areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;responsibilities-and-privileges&#34;&gt;Responsibilities and privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsive to issues and PRs assigned to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Active owner of code they have contributed (unless ownership is explicitly
transferred).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code is well tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tests consistently pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addresses bugs or issues discovered after code is accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members who frequently contribute code are expected to proactively perform code
reviews and work towards becoming an approver for the area that they are active
in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;approver&#34;&gt;Approver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code approvers are able to both review and approve code contributions. While
code review is focused on code quality and correctness, approval is focused on
holistic acceptance of a contribution including: backward / forward
compatibility, adhering to API and flag conventions, subtle performance and
correctness issues, interactions with other parts of the system, etc. Approver
status is scoped to a part of the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements-1&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following apply to the part of the codebase for which one would be an
approver in an OWNERS file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewer of the codebase for at least 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary reviewer for at least 10 substantial PRs to the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One path for getting the necessary reviews is to add yourself to the
&lt;code&gt;reviewers&lt;/code&gt; section of the OWNERS file. Note that this does not give you any
additional privileges. By having yourself listed in this section in OWNERS
file means that you will get PRs assigned to you for code review. Getting
added to &lt;code&gt;reviewers&lt;/code&gt; section is at the discretion of an approver after
enough evidence of quality contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewed at least 30 PRs to the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominated by an a WG lead (with no objections from other leads).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;responsibilities-and-privileges-1&#34;&gt;Responsibilities and privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following apply to the part of the codebase for which one would be an
approver in an OWNERS file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approver status can be a precondition to accepting large code contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate sound technical judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsible for project quality control via &lt;a href=&#34;./REVIEWING.md&#34;&gt;code reviews&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on holistic acceptance of contribution such as dependencies with other
features, backward / forward compatibility, API and flag definitions, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected to be responsive to review requests as per
&lt;a href=&#34;./REVIEWING.md&#34;&gt;community expectations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentor new contributors and project members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approve code contributions for acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approvers are also expected to participate in community contact rotations
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving/blob/main/support/COMMUNITY_CONTACTS.md&#34;&gt;Serving&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/main/support/COMMUNITY_CONTACTS.md&#34;&gt;Eventing&lt;/a&gt;)
to support users and keep test quality high, as well as release leads
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/pkg/blob/main/RELEASE-LEADS.md&#34;&gt;rotation&lt;/a&gt; to
shepherd Knative releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;working-group-leadership-roles&#34;&gt;Working Group Leadership Roles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We differentiate here between two key roles, WG Execution Lead and WG Technical
Lead. In small working groups, often these roles will be performed by one
person; in larger working groups it might be best to have different individuals
performing these roles. There is no &amp;lsquo;formula&amp;rsquo;, it is up to the working group
leadership to determine what is best for their working group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-group-technical-lead&#34;&gt;Working Group Technical Lead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working group technical leads, or just ‘tech leads’, are approvers of an entire
area that have demonstrated good judgement and responsibility. Tech leads accept
design proposals and approve design decisions for their area of ownership, and
are responsible for the overall technical health of their functional area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements-2&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting to be a tech lead of an existing working group:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognized as having expertise in the group’s subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approver for a relevant part of the codebase for at least 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Member for at least 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primary reviewer for 20 substantial PRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewed or merged at least 50 PRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by the technical oversight committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional requirements for leads of a new working group:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Originally authored or contributed major functionality to the group&amp;rsquo;s area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;responsibilities-and-privileges-2&#34;&gt;Responsibilities and privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following apply to the area / component for which one would be an owner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design/proposal approval authority over the area / component, though
escalation to the technical oversight committee is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical review of &lt;a href=&#34;./mechanics/FEATURE-TRACKS.md&#34;&gt;feature tracks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perform issue triage on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply/remove/create/delete GitHub labels and milestones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write access to repo (assign issues/PRs, add/remove labels and milestones,
edit issues and PRs, edit wiki, create/delete labels and milestones).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capable of directly applying lgtm + approve labels for any PR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expected to respect OWNERS files approvals and use
&lt;a href=&#34;./REVIEWING.md#merging-prs&#34;&gt;standard procedure for merging code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected to work to holistically maintain the health of the project through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing PRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixing bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identifying needed enhancements / areas for improvement / etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Execute pay-down of technical debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentoring and guiding approvers, members, and new contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-group-execution-lead&#34;&gt;Working Group Execution Lead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working group execution leads, or just ‘execution leads’, are responsible for
the overall health and execution of the working group itself. Execution leads
work with tech leads to ensure that the working group is making progress toward
its goals, is aligned with the project roadmap, etc. The execution lead may also
be the tech lead in a smaller working group, but they are distinct roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements-3&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participant in the working group for at least 3 months, for example as scribe
or approver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognized as having expertise in the group’s subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by the technical oversight committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;responsibilities-and-privileges-3&#34;&gt;Responsibilities and privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run their working group as explained in the
&lt;a href=&#34;./mechanics/WORKING-GROUP-PROCESSES.md&#34;&gt;Working Group Processes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meetings. Prepare the agenda and run the regular working group meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes. Ensure that meeting notes are kept up to date. Provide a link to the
recorded meeting in the notes. The lead may delegate note-taking duties to
the scribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roadmap. Establish and maintain a roadmap for the working group outlining
the areas of focus for the working group over the next 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Report. Report current status to the TOC meeting every 6 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holistic responsibility for their working group&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;./mechanics/FEATURE-TRACKS.md&#34;&gt;feature
tracks&lt;/a&gt;: tracking, health, and execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perform issue triage on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply/remove/create/delete GitHub labels and milestones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write access to repo (assign issues/PRs, add/remove labels and milestones,
edit project, issues, and PRs, edit wiki, create/delete labels and milestones).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected to work to holistically maintain the health of the working through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a good role model&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be an advocate for the working group inside and outside of the community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foster a welcoming and collegial environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentoring and guiding approvers, members, and new contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scribe&#34;&gt;Scribe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most underrated roles in open source projects is the role of note
taker. The importance and value of this role is frequently overlooked and
underestimated. Since one of the core project values is transparency, we have an
explicit scribe role to recognize these types of contributions. Working group
scribes assist the Working Group leads with the mechanical processes around
Working Group meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements-4&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participant in the working group for at least 1 month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pattern of attendance and note-taking during working group meetings and one-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by a working group execution or technical lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;responsibilities-and-privileges-4&#34;&gt;Responsibilities and privileges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attend working group meetings and one-offs whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that important information from meetings makes it into the WG notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post WG recordings to the team drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within this section &amp;ldquo;manager&amp;rdquo; refers to a member who is an Execution Lead, Tech
Lead, Approver or Scribe. (this is different from a WG or Organization Member).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial managers are defined at the founding of the WG or Subproject as part
of the acceptance of that WG or Subproject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managers SHOULD remain active and responsive in their Roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managers MUST be community members to be eligible to hold a leadership role within a SIG.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managers taking an extended leave of 1 or more months SHOULD coordinate with
other managers to ensure the role is adequately staffed during the leave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managers going on leave for 1-3 months MAY work with other managers to suggest
a replacement using the normal process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managers of a role SHOULD remove any other managers that have not communicated
a leave of absence and either cannot be reached for more than 1 month or are
not fulfilling their documented responsibilities for more than 1 month.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This MAY be done through a super-majority vote of managers, or if there are
not enough active managers to get a super-majority of votes cast, then
removal MAY occur through exception process to the TOC.  The PR removing the
manager should be open for at least 72 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior to voting to remove a manager, leads SHOULD reach out to the affected
manager and see if they need to take a leave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Membership disagreements MAY be escalated to the WG leads. WG lead membership
disagreements MAY be escalated to the TOC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managers MAY decide to step down at anytime and nominate a replacement who
will be approved through the regular process for that role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the hope of the steering committee that effective communication will make
the use of these rules something that happens under exceptional circumstances
only. In circumstances where it is unavoidable, these are presented so that the
process is clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: Reviewing and merging Knative pull requests</title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/reviewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/reviewing/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;As a community, we believe in the value of code reviews for all contributions.
Code reviews increase both the quality and readability of our code base, which
in turn produces high quality software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document provides guidelines for how the project&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;a href=&#34;./ROLES.md#member&#34;&gt;Members&lt;/a&gt; review issues and merge pull requests (PRs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#pull-requests-welcome&#34;&gt;Pull requests welcome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#code-reviewers&#34;&gt;Code reviewers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#reviewing-changes&#34;&gt;Reviewing changes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#holds&#34;&gt;Holds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#approvers&#34;&gt;Approvers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#merging-prs&#34;&gt;Merging PRs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pull-requests-welcome&#34;&gt;Pull requests welcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost: as a potential contributor, your changes and ideas are
welcome at any hour of the day or night, weekdays, weekends, and holidays.
Please do not ever hesitate to ask a question or submit a PR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewers are often the first points of contact between new members of the
community and are important in shaping the community. We encourage reviewers to
read the &lt;a href=&#34;./CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; and to go above and beyond the
code of conduct to promote a collaborative and respectful community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-reviewers&#34;&gt;Code reviewers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code review process can introduce latency for contributors and additional
work for reviewers, frustrating both parties. Consequently, as a community we
expect all active participants to also be active reviewers. Participate in the
code review process in areas where you have expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reviewing-changes&#34;&gt;Reviewing changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a PR has been submitted, reviewers should do an initial review to do a
quick &amp;ldquo;triage&amp;rdquo; (e.g. close duplicates, identify user errors, etc.), and
potentially identify which maintainers should be the focal points for the
review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a PR is closed without accepting the changes, reviewers are expected to
provide sufficient feedback to the originator to explain why it is being closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a review, PR authors are expected to respond to comments and questions
made within the PR - updating the proposed change as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a review of the proposed changes, reviewers can either approve or reject
the PR. To approve, they add an &amp;ldquo;approved&amp;rdquo; review to the PR. To reject, they add
a &amp;ldquo;request changes&amp;rdquo; review along with a full justification for why they are not
in favor of the change. If a PR gets a &amp;ldquo;request changes&amp;rdquo; vote, the group
discusses the issue to resolve their differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewers are expected to respond in a timely fashion to PRs that are assigned
to them. Reviewers are expected to respond to &lt;em&gt;active&lt;/em&gt; PRs with reasonable
latency. If reviewers fail to respond, those PRs may be assigned to other
reviewers. &lt;em&gt;Active&lt;/em&gt; PRs are those that have a proper CLA (&lt;code&gt;cla:yes&lt;/code&gt;) label, are
not works in progress (WIP), are passing tests, and do not need rebase to be
merged. PRs that do not have a proper CLA, are WIP, do not pass tests, or
require a rebase are not considered active PRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;holds&#34;&gt;Holds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any &lt;a href=&#34;./ROLES.md#approver&#34;&gt;Approver&lt;/a&gt; who wants to review a PR but does not have
time immediately can put a hold on a PR. If you need more time, say so on the PR
discussion and offer an ETA measured in single-digit days at most. Any PR that
has a hold will not be merged until the person who requested the hold acks the
review, withdraws their hold, or is overruled by a majority of approvers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;approvers&#34;&gt;Approvers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merging of PRs is done by &lt;a href=&#34;./ROLES.md#approver&#34;&gt;Approvers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is the case with many open source projects, becoming an Approver is based on
contributions to the project. See our &lt;a href=&#34;./ROLES.md&#34;&gt;community roles&lt;/a&gt; document for
information on how this is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;merging-prs&#34;&gt;Merging PRs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A PR can be merged only after the following criteria are met:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has no &amp;ldquo;request changes&amp;rdquo; review from a reviewer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has at least one &amp;ldquo;approved&amp;rdquo; review by at least one of the approvers of
that repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has all appropriate corresponding documentation and tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prow&#34;&gt;Prow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project uses
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/test-infra/tree/master/prow&#34;&gt;Prow&lt;/a&gt; to
automatically run tests for every PR. PRs with failing tests might not be
merged. If necessary, you can rerun the tests by simply adding the comment
&lt;code&gt;/retest&lt;/code&gt; to your PR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prow has several other features that make PR management easier, like running the
go linter or assigning labels. For a full list of commands understood by Prow,
see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://prow.knative.dev/command-help&#34;&gt;command help page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except as otherwise noted, the content of this page is licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License&lt;/a&gt;,
and code samples are licensed under the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/consensus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/consensus/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;As a community, Knative values lazy consensus as a decision-making tool. Having discussions about larger changes or contentious issues mainly over synchronous meetings makes it difficult for contributors in differing time zones to participate. Compounding the problem is the fact that there are also Slack conversations on various channels, emails, etc. that make it difficult to decipher what led to various decisions and what alternatives were considered and so forth. We use &amp;ldquo;lazy consensus&amp;rdquo; as a mode of operation towards asynchronous communication will help get to a healthier and more inclusive community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;when&#34;&gt;When&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lazy consensus is about decisions of consequence. This is a somewhat fuzzy concept, and we will not attempt to make a specific definition to be followed. Instead, this can be thought of as a judgement call to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decision of consequence is something that as a contributor, you or one of your open source colleagues would feel that they have a stake in. It might be something as specific as a polarizing pull request. It might be the direction a feature track will go in. It might be a plan within a working group for a refactoring. It may or may not have representation in github or a document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When deciding whether lazy consensus is required, you and your peers must think about the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would you feel if the decision was made without your input?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would your peers not present in the discussion feel if the decision was made without their input?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think about these questions and feel like your feelings or your colleagues&#39; feelings would be hurt if you or they were not given a stake in the decision, it’s time to use lazy consensus. If the answer isn’t clear, it’s time to use lazy consensus to err on the side of inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid debates about communication channels, we will have a process where one’s preferences of communication channels don’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When lazy consensus is used, you should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail the dev list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post a message in slack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post a comment on relevant github issues/PRs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The message content should clearly reference via link any PR, issue, or document related to the decision, and let the reader know where to engage in the discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think someone may be particularly interested, sending a message of some kind with a pointer to the public issue discussion may be appropriate. It is not appropriate to hash out all the details in a private discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow time for your colleagues to read and think about the message
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please allow an appropriate amount of time, at least 3 business days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give healthy consideration to reasonable objections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If consensus cannot be achieved within the discussion, you should attempt to resolve it within the appropriate working group, then engage the TOC or Steering as appropriate if that fails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record the decision in writing
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In increasing order of durability: decision announced in meeting minutes, send a mail to the mailing list, approval in Google Doc by WG lead, GitHub PR (possibly in “docs” directory or the like)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/security/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;knative-security-policy&#34;&gt;Knative security policy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To report a security issue, please email &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@knative.team&#34;&gt;security@knative.team&lt;/a&gt; with a description of the issue, the steps you took to create the issue, affected versions, and, if known, mitigations for the issue. Our vulnerability management team will respond within 3 working days of your email. If the issue is confirmed as a vulnerability, we will open a Security Advisory. This project follows a 90 day disclosure timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/client/charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/client/charter/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;knative-client-working-group-charter&#34;&gt;Knative Client Working Group Charter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knative Client Working Group maintains a delightful baseline operator-neutral Knative client developer experience, including documentation about what normative clients do, and a reference implementation of a normative client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a portable reference command-line client for Knative with a normative workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide guidance about normative uses of the Knative APIs to client developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide reference implementations of Knative developer workflows as a library to be incorporated into other clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a new repo in the knative org:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain documentation around how the API can be used to create a delightful user experience for core Developer journeys, and client conventions for Knative as a whole and each Knative building block.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and maintain a golang library for implementing the normative client flows for the Developer persona, for general Knative-wide conventions as well as workflows specific to each building block and their interactions. This library should support workflows for both graphical and command-line client tooling, though the group will only maintain an implementation of a command-line client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and maintain a standalone command-line client, &lt;code&gt;kn&lt;/code&gt;, using the aforementioned library, that implements a developer experience for Knative that is portable across operators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In working group meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a forum to discuss non-CLI user tooling as well (web, etc.), and how the client libraries can support those too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;non-scope&#34;&gt;Non-scope:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation of other experimental interfaces for Knative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-3-month-roadmap&#34;&gt;Preliminary 3-Month Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Month 1 (December. December barely exists.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get repo structure set up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start library for Serving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick tech stack for CLI (set of libs to use for terminal manipulation &amp;amp; display etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Month 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start CLI, using library for Serving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One major user journey complete for Serving, ex &amp;ldquo;deploy a new image to a Service&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With Build: Settle on supported path for deploy-from-source-dir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With Eventing: Discuss user support for discovery story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Month 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have at least two major user journeys completed e2e for Serving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;documentation-details&#34;&gt;Documentation details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New WG will own &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving/blob/master/docs/spec/normative_examples.md&#34;&gt;normative-examples.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/serving/blob/master/docs/client-conventions.md&#34;&gt;client-conventions.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; from Serving; similar docs can start here, concerning any of Serving, Eventing, Build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;library-details&#34;&gt;Library details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Go library implementing core Knative functionality for the Developer persona, including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Knative-wide functionality
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library for reading and dealing with ready conditions and terminal conditions.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching or polling them for completeness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting on partial completeness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for the core user journeys across Knative projects, including cross-project integrations. Examples:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploying software to Services
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploying from source: integrated with Build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploying an image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing the configurations of services
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resource limits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concurrency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rolling out traffic to revisions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rolling back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fetching and watching all Knative Serving objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build/Pipeline
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fetching build templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating builds using build templates
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a source repository version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a directory of source (possibly using a technique similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mattmoor/kontext#kontext&#34;&gt;Matt&amp;rsquo;s proof-of-concept&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating builds not using build templates (NB: Probably not part of most mainline developer experiences, but included for completeness)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating namespace-scoped build templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventing
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating bindings from events to endpoints in services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listing available event sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describing source capabilities and configuration options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating event source instances (diff between CRD defining the source and an actual instance of a source) in a generic way, these vary wildly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRUD on Channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A way to find unused channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any future Knative building blocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cli-details&#34;&gt;CLI details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A basic command-line client (or plugin to kubectl, chosen based on overall developer experience), built on the Go library, that provides a command-line interface for all the tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We like short command names. &lt;code&gt;kn&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication using kubeconfig&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Output formatting and filtering similar to kubectl (tabular, json, yaml formats, templating)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;responsibility-also-includes&#34;&gt;Responsibility also includes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests for all of the above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code coverage for all the above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any extra github automation for the repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;possible-future-scope&#34;&gt;Possible future scope:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client libs in other languages. (interest in py from google, at least)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;out-of-scope&#34;&gt;Out of scope:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operator concerns (Focusing the interface on the role of developer will lead to a better developer experience, and operator concerns are irrelevant to most developers. Also, operator concerns are more likely to involve non-Knative APIs, like RBAC)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installing cluster-scoped build templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installing Knative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making cluster-scoped configuration choices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any functionality that relies on non-Knative APIs (Knative clusters are built using a variety of features, due to the &amp;ldquo;pluggable backends&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;duck typing&amp;rdquo; work we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing, and so if an API hasn&amp;rsquo;t been standardized into Knative we can&amp;rsquo;t assume a Knative cluster has it)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Currently) exposing a service outside the cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RBAC management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binding a service to a domain name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installing Knative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any functionality that relies on a particular implementation of Knative. (Client libs should work the same against any implementation of Knative)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vendor extensions (aside from codifying where in the API they can go)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any particular happenstance/subtleties that aren&amp;rsquo;t codified, for example in exact ordering of conditions becoming True for a happy-path operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conformance tests for Knative. These can and should &lt;strong&gt;use&lt;/strong&gt; the client libraries we&amp;rsquo;re working on, but deserve their own home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-group&#34;&gt;Working Group&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a peer of the other Knative working groups, run weekly (to start), cancelled when we don&amp;rsquo;t have enough to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/delivery/charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/delivery/charter/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;knative-event-delivery-working-group-charter&#34;&gt;Knative Event Delivery Working Group Charter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Updated: Nov 15, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: the original document was written to focus on Knative Channels, but the TOC recommended refocusing on consistent data-plane behavior and the group renamed. The charter still contains many references to Channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knative Event Delivery Working Group will reduce the friction of finding, implementing, and using Knative compliant Channels. We will specify the interface for event delivery such that multiple implementations can be used by higher level pieces. As well as create conformance tests to verify a given implementation implements the interface correctly and make that information available for operators and developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event Delivery is the fundamental data-plane building block for most of the Eventing working group&amp;rsquo;s APIs, including: Broker, Parallel, and Sequence. The stability and reliability of event delivery is thus critical for the majority of Eventing API&amp;rsquo;s surface area. Due to the importance of event delivery, this newly proposed Working Group will lead the Spec, API, documentation as well as conformance test in a focused way, helping implementers of eventing components and other APIs depending on event delivery, to guarantee a consistent and efficient data tranfer API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect that other working groups will focus on how channels are used and in particular creating working group for Broker, Parallel, and Sequence (and similar higher level constructs) if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/master/docs/personas.md#event-consumer-developer&#34;&gt;Event Consumer&lt;/a&gt;, the choice of Channel implementation with identical defined characteristics (e.g. persistence or in-order delivery) has no affect on me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/master/docs/personas.md#event-producer&#34;&gt;Event Producer&lt;/a&gt;, the choice of Channel implementation has no affect on me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/master/docs/personas.md#system-integrator&#34;&gt;System Integrator&lt;/a&gt;, I can create a new Channel implementation and use the conformance tests to verify that it meets all the requirements of a Channel implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As an Operator, I can find conforming Channel implementations and control which are available within the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As an Operator, I can choose Channels based on additional, well defined characteristics, such as persistence or in-order delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As an Operator, I can understand Channel usage and locate errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the existing Eventing repo inside the knative org:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to evolve the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/master/docs/spec/channel.md&#34;&gt;Channel Spec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to increase the coverage of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/tree/master/test/conformance&#34;&gt;Channel conformance tests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/tree/master/docs/delivery&#34;&gt;Channel error handling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain libraries to make Channels more consistent, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/master/pkg/channel/event_receiver.go&#34;&gt;EventReceiver&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/master/pkg/channel/event_dispatcher.go&#34;&gt;EventDispatcher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain OWNERS files within both the eventing and eventing-contrib repo for folders owned by the Channels WG. So that it is easier to track who is on track PRs and who is on track to become an approver or lead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document and evolve the event delivery contract between all Knative pieces dealing with events, and manifest this contract in a “Knative Event Delivery Spec”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore different styles of Channel implementations, giving nuanced recommendations on the trade-offs between different designs (e.g. Job based vs singleton dispatchers).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain a list of conforming &lt;a href=&#34;https://knative.dev/docs/eventing/channels/channels-crds/&#34;&gt;Channel implementations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In working group meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a forum to discuss and align work items related to the working group, status updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-3-month-roadmap&#34;&gt;Preliminary 3-Month Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start to define the Event Delivery Spec.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify the Channel Spec and reflect content from Event Delivery Spec.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InMemoryChannel has error handling (dead letter queue).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document the different styles of Channels that currently exist and their trade offs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase the amount of the specification covered by the conformance tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one Channel implementation other than InMemoryChannel has error handling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase the amount of the specification covered by the conformance tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add observability to the Channel specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one Channel uses native error handling (e.g. RabbitMQ&amp;rsquo;s dead letter exchange).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% coverage of all MUST and MUST NOT directives in the specification covered by the conformance tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Framework for the conformance tests to test optional Channel attributes, such as guaranteed delivery and in-order delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least two Channel implementations that pass all conformance tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document which Channel implementations are available, whether they pass conformance tests, and any optional properties they guarantee (e.g. persistence, in order delivery, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-group&#34;&gt;Working Group&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will operate as a partner group to Eventing, giving a brief update in the weekly Eventing working group meeting. We will additionally meet on a weekly basis, cancelled when there is a lack of agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposed-leads&#34;&gt;Proposed Leads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Harwayne&#34;&gt;Harwayne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matzew&#34;&gt;matzew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eventing WG created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1uxlulaAf2m_yZUqCIeI-inul2gsqP69PElnZdO0FHUo/edit#&#34;&gt;Channel Task Force&lt;/a&gt; in May 2019, lead by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Harwayne&#34;&gt;Harwayne&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matzew&#34;&gt;matzew&lt;/a&gt;. It has been meeting on a weekly basis and has made progress on many of the issues above. As the scope of the task force has increased, it no longer has a clear exit condition. Therefore it feels more appropriate for it to be a working group, rather than a task force.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/docs/charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/docs/charter/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;knative-documentation-working-group-charter&#34;&gt;Knative Documentation Working Group Charter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors: Sam O’Dell, (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:odells@google.com&#34;&gt;odells@google.com&lt;/a&gt;), Richie Escarez (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:rescarez@google.com&#34;&gt;rescarez@google.com&lt;/a&gt;), Ivan Nikittin (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ifnikitt@google.com&#34;&gt;ifnikitt@google.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To write, edit, review, organize, and maintain contributions to the Knative open source documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a first-class documentation experience for Knative users by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establishing a documentation strategy and aligning new contributions with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining style guidelines and terminology for the doc set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating the efforts of documentation contributors and encouraging new contributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopting appropriate tooling to help with automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating processes that:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower the time to address PRs and issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protect the quality of the documentation, especially over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributing to overall product direction through our experience as the earliest Knative users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This group will primarily concern itself with the content of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/docs&#34;&gt;Knative Docs repo&lt;/a&gt;, but may also contribute to the documentation in other &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative&#34;&gt;Knative&lt;/a&gt; repos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;documentation-working-group-roadmap&#34;&gt;Documentation Working Group Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1A0H2lpH8FQ0RQxkdXbLz-tbFsM4qtUByARPHkLuDOdw/edit#&#34;&gt;Link to Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/operations/charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/operations/charter/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;knative-operations-working-group-charter&#34;&gt;Knative Operations Working Group Charter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created: 2019-04-26 / Last Updated: 2019-05-06&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charter&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knative Operation Working Group provides best practices for managing, assessing system health and maintaining Knative clusters. The initial focus will be on how Knative is installed, removed, and upgraded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a means to install Knative [Serving/Build/Eventing] with operator(s) specified options
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operator specified defaults such as timeouts and concurrency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network preferences, Istio / Gloo / others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build Template selection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventing component selection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a means to install Knative with limited/no internet access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a means to upgrade/downgrade Knative with limited/no user visible impact to their service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide guidelines on determining the overall health of Knative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide cluster sizing and lifecycle recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An entrypoint and forum for dogfooders to give feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;non-goals&#34;&gt;Non-Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The knative operator does not manage or install Istio, or other dependents.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But we might want to have the option to recommend other operators for this task. Like &lt;code&gt;knative.spec.istioOperator = yes&lt;/code&gt; please.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tooling for installation/removal/upgrades/downgrades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management mechanisms for:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;namespace setup (if needed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quota and RBAC management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build and registry configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;integration with existing cluster o11y&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging tools for operator personas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define more specific &amp;ldquo;operator&amp;rdquo; sub-personas within the Knative &amp;ldquo;operator&amp;rdquo; persona (e.g. auditor, cloud provider, IT provider, etc)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect feedback from operators on the usability of Knative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate w/ Documentation Working Group on documentation for installation/removal/upgrades/downgrades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate w/ Observability Working Group on metrics for health of Knative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate w/ Productivity Working Group on using best-practice installation for testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lead-nomination&#34;&gt;Lead Nomination&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Browning (bbrowning), Gregory Haynes (greghaynes), Kenny Leung (k4leung4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;roadmap&#34;&gt;Roadmap*&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 1 ~ Knative 0.7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement all tasks under &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/community/blob/master/WORKING-GROUP-PROCESSES.md#setting-up-a-working-group&#34;&gt;Setting Up A Working Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up separate repo for each of Knative serving/eventing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable operator installs for current version of Knative Serving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 2 ~ Knative 0.8&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopt operator installation usage for automated Knative Serving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on parameters for customization for Knative Serving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable operator installs for Knative Build/Eventing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 3 ~ Knative 0.9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate using operator for test execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore upgrade scenarios for Knative Serving using operator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assumes adoption of operators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;previous-efforts&#34;&gt;Previous Efforts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/open?id=11cenPfZrEU04OFQYTE_6e_LrOw07HPOkeT1_Gigmy7U&#34;&gt;Knative Operator Working Group Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/productivity/charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/productivity/charter/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;contributor-productivity-working-group-charter&#34;&gt;Contributor Productivity Working Group Charter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the proposal of creating contributor productivity working group for Knative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mission of Contributor Productivity working group is to develop engineering guidelines, tools and infrastructure for Knative open source community to enable high quality and high velocity deliverables, to drive measurable and predictable releases, and to achieve high community collaboration and overall productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foster collaboration among contributors for common needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify top priorities or pain points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formulate guidelines and processes around testing, continuous integration, code velocity, and release packaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop/Evangelize reusable tools and infrastructure to be utilized by contributors across repos for various purposes such as E2E testing, conformance testing, performance/scalability testing, project health reporting, product troubleshooting/diagnostics and etc. More specifically we’d graduate reusable tools to kubernetes/test-infra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive up contributor experience with ongoing improvements to automations around code life cycle such as issue creation, triage, code review, test and release. The goal is to reduce contributor overhead, minimize product defects and improve overall efficiency. In turn, it shall help developer and operator experience with better product quality and more efficient releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project health
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define metrics (such as listed below) to measure project health, and deliver automation for improving project health.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release churns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PR latency (time to merge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboarding velocity (time to PR)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issue Triage velocity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issue Resolving Velocity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have automation in place to help drive up project health metrics with opt-in (default off) vs. opt-out (default on) options; and each WG can decide whether they are in or out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test framework
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure there is common test infrastructure in place to run unit, build, E2E and conformance tests, to output logs and metrics from tests, and to visualize logs/metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CI/CD workflows
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain presubmit and postsubmit workflows to gate the quality of code checkin and quality of release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure there is sufficient monitoring in place to monitor the health of workflow and infrastructure themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release criteria/process
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define and implement release criteria and process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1_LXxZc_dlmFexILC27TnitFSFxP3l9mUkmGf_uTRYHc/edit&#34;&gt;Performance/Scalability/Load testing&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with individual feature WG (serving, scaling, build, control plane, eventing) to identify common requirements and provide a shared framework for each WG to consume. Initial thinking of common need includes cluster creation/setup, load profiles, test orchestration, result collection, metric visualization and etc. The corresponding framework code will exist at test-infra repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual feature WG will be responsible for designing and implementing the actual testing, the corresponding test code will exist at individual repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with partner teams to reuse existing performance/load testing infrastructure as well as environment whenever possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link above has more detailed proposals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting experience
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure sufficient automation and documentation is in place for self-service Knative troubleshooting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will use Knative/test-infra repo for code, maybe a good idea to rename it for broader purpose as outlined in this doc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;initial-set-of-leads&#34;&gt;Initial set of leads:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adriano Cunha (adrcunha on github)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessie Zhu (jessiezcc on github)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;proposed-3-month-roadmap&#34;&gt;Proposed 3 Month Roadmap&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M8:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up regular WG meetings and establish forms of communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M9:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document existing development/release workflows to form a common understanding within the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect feedback on onboarding/development experience from the community from various sources such as meetings, slack, social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define performance/load testing goals for different scenarios (contributor vs. developer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finalize methodologies for perf/load testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M10:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build tools to measure community satisfaction around onboarding, developer, test, troubleshoot experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributor friendly onboarding &amp;amp; troubleshooting experience based on feedbacks from M8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one WG adopting perf/load test infra (scaling)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project health dashboard open to community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M11
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shareable performance/load test toolset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build tools to gather and track structured community feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive up community satisfaction based on measurements from M9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/security/charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/security/charter/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;security-working-group-charter&#34;&gt;Security Working Group Charter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “aaS” in FaaS stands for “as-a-service”. Many users would like to use Knative as the basis of a multi-tenant FaaS or PaaS-style platform. Even users who do not need hard multi-tenancy will wish to be confident of Knative’s security in single-tenant and soft multi-tenant scenarios. Currently the project provides limited guidance for how to configure and deploy itself successfully in these environments. The Security Working Group’s mission will be to fix this, by improving documentation, code, and process as needed to harden Knative for these use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Security Working Group is responsible for helping users successfully run Knative in security sensitive environments. This mission will involve documentation, proactive exploratory testing, fixing of gaps, and production of necessary manifests and example security policies for various use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Working Group will evaluate new and existing features for their security impact, and where necessary will work with other Working Groups to add features and close gaps in order to support security-sensitive and multi-tenant use cases. The overarching goal is to, as well as to promote a security-conscious mindset throughout the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example features and tasks which could fit within this mission (see also “Goals”, below):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documented recommendations and example manifests for setting up NetworkPolicy to prevent access between namespaces and for enabling mTLS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documented recommendations and example manifests for securing traffic between Eventing and Serving workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filling gaps in the security story for integrating eventing and serving. .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document how to expose Knative as a multi-tenant service. For example configuring a secure runtime (gVisor, Kata containers, firecracker etc), adding the AlwaysPullImages admission controller and appropriate security policies, setting up appropriate NetworkPolicy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documenting and improving the current security posture of Knative for various specific use cases, such as multi-tenant environments, air-gapped environments, and security-sensitive single tenant environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A suggested PodSecurityPolicy (or OPA policy etc) to be used with Knative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests and configuration to run Knative with gVisor, ClearContainers, and other isolation technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with open source security tools, eg. Falco.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up and maintaining Security Scanners, Linters and other automated tools (and initially fixing any found problems).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining processes for reporting, handling and pro-actively auditing the system for vulnerabilities; for example organising exploratory testing sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining and owning the process for handling reported security vulnerabilities (but see “non-goals” section w.r.t.not directly handling vulnerability reports, since this likely would mandate a restricted membership group).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-group&#34;&gt;Working Group&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this work cross-cuts Serving, Eventing, and Documentation, and since Security and Multi-tenancy are on-going considerations for the project, this will be a top-level working group which will work closely with other working groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that documentation and sample configs exist which permit Knative to be deployed securely (to the extent possible) in security-sensitive and multi-tenant environments. Close gaps (working with other WGs) and add features as needed to make this possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share and document best practices between those using Knative for security-sensitive use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide example configurations that lock down the upstream cluster to maximize security (i.e. to configure the system so that only the Knative APIs are available, and security-sensitive fields such as securityContext and serviceAccountTokens are blocked).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validate new feature proposals for their ability to be implemented in secure and multi-tenant environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider the API surface of Knative to identify and fix potential DOS attacks and other security vulnerabilities, and to ensure Knative can be successfully used in multi-tenant environments, and for security-sensitive use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish design docs on Knative Threat Model, Security Analysis docs etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up processes to ensure ongoing security of the platform. For example security linters, scanners, fuzzers, patch managers, and at a higher level through ensuring security is considered holistically and pro-actively by the project as a whole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a (ideally regular) brainstorming/exploratory session where we proactively brainstorm, investigate and mitigate potential attack vectors against the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-goals&#34;&gt;Non-Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard multi-tenancy in the unrestricted upstream platform. We will seek to upstream features as needed, but we assume achieving the goal for Knative in the short term may imply blocking access to some features in the underlying platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guaranteeing the security of the platform - this is ultimately up to vendors, administrators and operators; the WG mission is to provide guidance and share best practices to enable these people to be successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsibility for specific vulnerabilities (though the WG may be a good place to define and steward a general process for handling vulnerabilities, security scanning etc, actively being responsible for managing specific reported vulnerabilities would likely require a closed WG).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-existing-repos&#34;&gt;In the existing repos:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide cross-cutting input on security and multi-tenancy concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide documentation and example configurations for deploying Knative in multi-tenant environments, for example PodSecurityPolicies, NetworkPolicies, Secure Runtimes (some of this might end up being in a different repo).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill gaps needed to use securely, as appropriate. For example rate limiting for DOS attack mitigation, network policy, podsecuritypolicy (or related new hotness as it’s deprecated :)).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up &amp;amp; own automation and security scanning tools, linters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up &amp;amp; own test infrastructure for deploying and testing against an environment with limited RBAC rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-working-group-meetings&#34;&gt;In working group meetings:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a forum to discuss and document security-sensitive use cases, experiences and requirements, and to surface gaps and needed features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a forum to discuss potential new feature proposals WRT security and multi-tenant/security-sensitive-single-tenant use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform pro-active exploratory testing for vulnerabilities, DOS vectors etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss, prioritise and document the current and desired security posture of the project with regard to various scenarios (e.g. security-sensitive single tenant, air-gapped, multi-tenant etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-3-month-roadmap&#34;&gt;Preliminary 3-month Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document, with appropriate warnings about limitations, the current security recommendations for deploying Knative in various environments, for example hosted multi-tenant, private/trusted multi-tenant, secure single tenant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide and document an optional set of RBAC rules, PodSecurityPolicies etc which give access only to public Knative APIs, and block access to insecure features (securityContext, service tokens etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define and document a process for reporting and handling vulnerabilities (see discussion in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/community/pull/258&#34;&gt;https://github.com/knative/community/pull/258&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up infrastructure and CI automation to test changes against a restricted-RBAC, restricted PodSecurityPolicy environment. Close any found gaps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define and add a security section to the Project Proposal Template to ensure we explicitly consider security implications of new features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with Networking WG, create NetworkPolicies to secure access between namespaces and between the knative-serving namespace and container namespaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-future-6-12-month-items&#34;&gt;Potential Future (6-12 month) Items&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work with Eventing and Serving WG to provide secure communication between Events and Services in as networking-provider agnostic a way as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with Documentation WG, provide deployment instructions for configuring Knative with a secure container runtime (e.g., gVisor, Kata Containers)&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposed-leads&#34;&gt;Proposed Leads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julian Friedman (IBM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evan Anderson (VMware)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/security/responding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/security/responding/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;vulnerability-disclosure-response-policy&#34;&gt;Vulnerability Disclosure Response Policy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project follows the following process when responding to vulnerabilities
raised via the Security Disclosure Process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;product-security-taskforce-membership&#34;&gt;Product Security Taskforce Membership&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subset of maintainers who are subscribed to the &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@knative.team&#34;&gt;security@knative.team&lt;/a&gt; email
address form the Product Security Taskforce.
This group will be responsible for fixing vulnerabilities and managing the
disclosure process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Product Security Taskforce is distinct from the embargo list: it is not
necessary (or helpful) to join the PST in order to receive early notice of
vulnerabilities. The PST is intentionally small to avoid inadvertent
disclosures of vulnerabilities (while being large enough to spread the work of
responding to vulnerabilities) and should be composed of those who will
actively work on the fix and disclosure process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is an Approver, Lead or TOC Member in a Knative Project, or who is
an employee of a member of the Embargo list working in a security role may
apply to be a member of this group.
The application is approved or rejected by the TOC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identifying-a-fix-lead&#34;&gt;Identifying a Fix Lead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PST Fix Lead Role is responsible for initially responding to
vulnerabilities sent to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@knative.team&#34;&gt;security@knative.team&lt;/a&gt;, and for coordinating and
managing the response with the rest of the PST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use a rota system to assign the default PST Lead role.
All members of the PST are expected to sign up to the rota.
Regardless of the rota, another member of the PST may volunteer to be the PST
lead for a particular vulnerability.
This may be appropriate, for example, when the vulnerability is in a particular
area of the code that PST member is familiar with, or when the rota-ed PST lead
is already handing another vulnerability.
&lt;strong&gt;To avoid any confusion, if the PST Lead role is transferred, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.faasafety.gov/gslac/ALC/course_content.aspx?cID=36&amp;amp;sID=196&amp;amp;preview=true&#34;&gt;positive hand-off&lt;/a&gt;
should be performed (&amp;ldquo;you are the PST Lead for X&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ok, I am the PST Lead for X&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Great, you are the PST lead for X!&amp;quot;)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organising-the-fix-team&#34;&gt;Organising the Fix Team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fix Lead will quickly identify relevant engineers from the affected
projects/areas/working groups and the PST and add those engineers to the
security disclosure / email thread. This group becomes the Fix Team for the
vulnerability. To prevent accidental disclosure and to maximize efficiency of
response, the Fix Team should be the minimal size required for efficient
response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Given the current size of the project it is likely that in many cases the
Fix Team will be the entire PST, possibly with an additional engineer or
engineers for the affected area if the PST does not have relevant expertise
itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Fix Team decides the disclosure is in fact a vulnerability which should
be fixed, the Fix Lead will create a Github Security Advisory and provide the
Fix Team access to a private branch to develop the fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;developing-a-fix-and-managing-disclosures&#34;&gt;Developing a Fix and Managing Disclosures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;within-1-7-days-of-disclosure&#34;&gt;Within 1-7 Days of Disclosure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities are evaluated based on the Knative Threat Model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fix Team will create a CVSS using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.first.org/cvss/calculator/3.0&#34;&gt;CVSS calculator&lt;/a&gt;.
The Fix Lead makes the final call on the calculated CVSS; it is better to
move quickly than making the CVSS perfect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the Fix Team determines this is not a vulnerability based on the Knative
Threat Model, the discloser is notified and the process ends.&lt;/strong&gt;
(Note that in all cases it is important to inform the reporter that
the disclosure has been seen and is being addressed as quickly as possible).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, the Fix Lead creates a private branch for development of the Fix,
and a Github Security Advisory to coordinate the disclosure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fix Lead responds to the reporter to let them know the work has begun to
address the vulnerability. &lt;strong&gt;If appropriate, and if the reporter is willing,
the reporter is added to the Security Advisory and can help to develop the
fix. The reporter may also wish to help with writing the CVE entry. They
should in all cases be asked if they would like credit for identifying the
vulnerability in the CVE and disclosure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fix Team urgently develops a fix or mitigation so that a realistic
timeline can be communicated to users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fix Lead completes the Github Security Advisory and requests a CVE from Github.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the CVSS score is below 4.0, the Fix Team may - after appropriate
discussion and based on developer bandwidth, public holidays etc - decide to
slow down the release process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fact that a vulnerability has been disclosed and a fix will be released
is communicated by the Fix Lead (working with the Fix Team) to the
knative-security-announce mailing list with an exact date and time planned
for the disclosure. If the optional embargoed disclosure step will be
followed (see next section), this date must be three weeks from when the
disclosure is released to the embargo list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This email should be actionable: it should be clear when users
should block time to apply patches, what mitigations are available (if
appropriate), etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;optional-within-1-14-days-of-disclosure-private-embargoed-disclosure&#34;&gt;Optional, Within 1-14 Days of Disclosure (Private, Embargoed Disclosure)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If, in the judgement of the Fix Lead, a private disclosure is warranted, the
Embargo List is emailed with details of the fix (including any proposed
patch/mitigation and actionable instructions) and the date it will be
publicly disclosed and released.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If this is the case, the Public Disclosure should not be
released until at least three weeks after this notification is sent, to give
vendors time to prepare to release the patch. In exceptional circumstances
this may be extended to four weeks to account for significant public
holidays etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: This step is optional and should be reserved for significant
vulnerabilities that warrant this treatment. In general these are
vulnerabilities that could lead to remotely exploitable or privilege
escalation issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the unlikely event that a member of the PST list breaks embargo, or if
the exploit otherwise becomes public early, the PST Lead will decide whether
to accelerate the schedule for public disclosure and release of the fix.
When in doubt push forward and go public ASAP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;within-1-28-days-of-disclosure-fix-release-day&#34;&gt;Within 1-28 Days of Disclosure (Fix Release Day)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fix Lead cherry-picks the fix on to the main branch and all relevant
release branches and creates PRs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintainers should approve this PR as quickly as possible (it should already
have been reviewed on the private branch).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If necessary, Release jobs should be manually triggered to ensure
a release is available as quickly as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Issue should be disclosed to the knative-security-annnounce mailing
list, the knative-users mailing list, the knative-dev mailing list
and the embargo list including relevant PRs, mitigations and the release
numbers containing the fix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fix Lead removes any permissions from private branches granted for the
purposes of the Fix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;retrospective&#34;&gt;Retrospective&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://landing.google.com/sre/book/chapters/postmortem-culture.html&#34;&gt;blameless retrospective&lt;/a&gt;
should be conducted 1-3 days after the release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fix Lead will send a retrospective of the process to knative-dev
including details on everyone involved, the timeline of the process, links
to relevant PRs that introduced the issue, if relevant, and any critiques of
the response and release process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintainers and Fix Team are also encouraged to send their own feedback on
the process to knative-dev. Honest critique is the only way we are going to
get good at this as a community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document borrows heavily and gratefully from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/envoyproxy/envoy/blob/main/SECURITY.md&#34;&gt;Envoy Vulnerability
Response Process&lt;/a&gt;
and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/oss-vulnerability-guide/blob/main/guide.md&#34;&gt;Google OSS Vulnerability Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: </title>
      <link>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/sources/charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://knative.dev/community/contributing/working-groups/sources/charter/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;knative-sources-working-group-charter&#34;&gt;Knative Sources Working Group Charter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Scott Nichols&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Updated: Oct 30, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mission&#34;&gt;Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Knative Sources Working Group will reduce the friction of creating, finding, and implementing Knative compliant Sources. We will enable new ways to create, test, install, deploy and observe applications that produce or bridge events onto a cluster for consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a Developer Persona, enabling the creation of custom sources from new or existing code/containers with little to no changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a Developer Persona, allow for easy understanding of existing and potential sources installed in a cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As an Operator, installing new sources is trivial, and not a burden on the overall health of the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a Contributor, enable new methods for allowing new sources to be created allowing for user provided code and containers to adhere to the source specification defined by Knative Eventing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the existing Eventing repo inside the knative org:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to evolve the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/master/docs/spec/sources.md&#34;&gt;Source Spec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand on the Pod-Specible Sources work &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/159-xjBwougBWHOigWUk42tHSB_T1As6zdPwb_9zK38s/edit#heading=h.n8a530nnrb&#34;&gt;outlined&lt;/a&gt;, and POC &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/n3wscott/sources&#34;&gt;implemented&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore the concept of sidecars that enable and extend existing pods to emit CloudEvents, implement overrides, and possibly dynamically update the sink target based on configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage the POC from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Harwayne/auto-container-source&#34;&gt;Auto-Container-Source&lt;/a&gt; and expand it to include all implemented Pod-Specable sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide examples of custom sources implemented in several languages (Go, Java, Javascript, Python).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide SDK and test suite for event sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide test conformance suite to verify existing and knative sources are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/knative/eventing/blob/master/docs/spec/sources.md&#34;&gt;Source Spec&lt;/a&gt; compatible (and versioned). Run automatic tests and publish results for official and nonofficial knative sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with CLI for good UX on creating and discovery of Sources installed and/or running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In working group meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a forum to discuss and align work items related to the working group, status updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources WG Overall responsibility:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining Sources inside of knative/eventing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advising compatibility with Source contracts contributed to Knative inside of knative/eventing-contrib.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensuring that there are high-quality Sources for the most important (as decided by the WG) event-producing systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing and directing the larger Source-authoring ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracking long-term efforts around improving the efficiency of Sources when working in coordination with other Knative Eventing components (e.g. upstream filter propagation, batching, or other optimizations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preliminary-3-month-roadmap&#34;&gt;Preliminary 3-Month Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish principles of Sources (as both Developer and Operator Personas).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define Pod-Specable Run Time Contract (Ref: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/n3wscott/sources/blob/master/docs/runtime-contract.md&#34;&gt;work in progress&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement 3 Pod-Specable (TBD: DeploymentSource, JobSource, CronJobSource) sources in the sources.knative.dev API group inside of Eventing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deprecate ContainerSource and CronJobSource in sources.eventing.knative.dev.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrate to new api group: ‘sources.knative.dev’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage with CLI to develop a long term UX plan for creation of sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement 3 more Pod-Specable Sources (TBD: DaemonSource, StatefulSetSource, ServiceSource)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable Auto*Source for 2-3 sources (TBD: DeploymentSource, ServiceSource).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement Conformance Test for runtime contract of Pod-Specable Sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage with Operator to see path forward for additional source installations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Began implementing example sources for 1-2 languages for 1-2 Source types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CLI is able to discover and create Sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start Sidecar and usability research for Advanced Lazy Sources..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Month 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CLI can create and discover Sources from labeled CRDs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement remaining Pod-Specable resources (TBD: ReplicaSet, Pod)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable Auto*Source for remaining Sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement Examples for remaining languages as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operator integration has been determined and work is ongoing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TBD: Additional Sidecar work per results of Advanced Lazy Sources research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-group&#34;&gt;Working Group&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will operate as a partner group to Eventing, giving a brief update in the weekly Eventing working group meeting. We may additionally meet on a weekly basis, cancelled when there is a lack of agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nominated-leads&#34;&gt;Nominated Leads:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nacho Cano, Scott Nichols, Ville Aikas, Lionel Villard&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
